I've always known this day would come.
我就知道会有这么一天
Detective Takagi finally did it!
高木警官终于做到了！
But...
但是…
It was announced so suddenly...
这决定真的好突然…
Will he really come?
他真的会来吗?
It's an anonymous tip-off.
这是个匿名举报
The chances are slim.
机会渺茫
This is the man, right?
就是这个男人 对吧？
(One police officer dead) The one who caused your classmate to...
是他把你的同期给…
Sorry, I shouldn't have said that.
对不起 我不该这么说…
It's bothering me.
但我还是搞不懂
(Related to the bombing incident) He might be skilled in bombs,
懂炸弹是一回事 但我不认为他有设计和执行逃跑计划的能力
In other words...
也就是说…
Wow!
哇！
Detective Sato is beautiful!
佐藤警官好漂亮啊！
Someday, Ran and I...
我跟兰总有一天也会…
What's wrong, Conan?
怎么了 柯南？
Huh? I-It's nothing!
啊？没什么！
This kid is thinking of marrying you, isn't he?
这小子想娶你 是吧？
No way!
怎么可能！
She's right...
她说得对…
Wataru Takagi, do you promise
高木涉 你愿意…
to protect and make Miwako happy for the rest of your life?
保护美和子让她一生幸福吗？
I do!
是 我愿意！
Miwako, do you promise
美和子 你愿意
- Help me! - to be a pillar of support
救我！- 美和子 你愿意
- What was that? - to Wataru no matter what,
那是什么？- 无论任何时候
and continue to love him for the rest of your life?
并一辈子爱着他吗？
- I-- - Miwako!
是...- 美和子！
If you're marrying that jerk, then I might as well kill you!
如果你要嫁给这个混蛋的话我就把你杀了！
Restrain them!
逮捕他们！
- Uncle? - Move aside!
叔叔？ - 让开！
H-Hold on!
等等！
That hurts, you idiot!
很痛啊 笨蛋！
What's going on?!
这是怎么一回事？
Capture him!
抓住他！
This is bad!
糟糕！
Darn! These aren't the right shoes...
完了！不是这双鞋子…
Kazami! Step aside!
风见！躲开！
Save me!
救救我！
Kazami, are you okay...
风见 你没事吧…
Kazami!
风见！
Takagi!
高木！
End of the drill!
演习结束！
Huh?
嗯？
What? Did we lose?
什么？我们被骗了？
Really?
真的假的？
What were you guys doing?
你们在干什么啊？
The groom got shot!
新郎中枪了 不是吗？
Let's revise the security formation!
我们来改进一下安保阵型！
This paint won't come off easily, huh?
这颜料很难洗掉吧？
What's wrong, Sato?
怎么了 佐藤？
N-Nothing's wrong.
没什么
What is going on?!
这是怎么一回事？
This doesn't make sense.
这一点都不对劲
Isn't this supposed to be Detective Takagi and Detective Sato's wedding ceremony?
这不是高木警官和佐藤警官的婚礼吗？
Oh no, I'm sorry.
不是 很抱歉
I wanted the drill to be as real as possible, so you weren't told anything.
我想要这场演习越真实越好所以没提前告诉你们
Hey, hey...
喂 喂…
Tsutomu Muranaka, the former Senior Superintendent, is going to get married.
其实是前高级警司村中努要结婚了
The police and Mouri are in charge of the security for his wedding.
毛利和我负责他婚礼的安保
Dad, you knew about this?
爸 你一直都知道吗？
- Yeah, sorry about that. - That's why you were able to act quickly...
是的 很抱歉- 怪不得你能那么快就作出反应...
You and Former Senior Superintendent Muranaka were from the same year, right?
前高级警司村中是你的同期吧？
Yeah, among all of us, he was the most successful.
是的 他是我们当中事业最成功的
He got injured a few years ago and left the force.
他几年前受了伤 离开了警队
Then, he met his now-fiancée at the hospital he was in.
然后在医院里遇到了他命中注定的缘分
I was worried because he never contacted me after he left.
我本来还担心他离开后会和我失去联络
Frankly speaking, I was shocked.
说实话 我很震惊
But why is Division 1 responsible for the security of the ceremony?
为什么要让刑事部搜查一课负责婚礼的安保呢？
Muranaka received a threat.
村中收到了一封恐吓信
When he was in service, he arrested many criminals.
他在任期间抓了很多犯人
A lot of people still resent him even now.
到现在还有很多怨恨他的人
So they are out for vengeance?
所以他们要来寻仇吗？
Indeed.
是的
That's why we requested to let us take charge of security.
所以我们要求警视厅高层
We know the faces of the criminals Muranaka arrested.
我们认得被村中抓过的犯人的长相
I thought that
如果真有人寻仇…
if it does happen, we'd be able to handle it...
我想我们能应付得来…
Are you alright, Miwako?
你没事吧 美和子？
I'll bring some water.
我去给你倒一杯水
It's been three years...
已经三年了…
As I thought, it was you.
果然是你
If he escapes, then I would show up.
只要帮他逃走就能引我现身
That's what you predicted, right?
这在你的预料之内吧？
What's wrong, Detective Sato?
怎么了 佐藤警官?
Conan...
柯南…
It's nothing...
没什么…
Even if I say that, you'd see right through me, huh?
就算我这样说 你也能马上把我看透
When Takagi collapsed earlier...
刚才高木倒下的时候…
I saw 'that' again...
我又看见“那个”了…
'That'?
那个？
What do you mean by 'that'?
那个是什么？
The one trying to take Takagi away...
想把高木带走的…
The Grim Reaper.
死神…
My name is Shinichi Kudo, a high school detective.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
When I went to the theme park with my childhood friend, Ran,
当我和青梅竹马毛利兰一起到游乐园游玩时
I witnessed a suspicious transaction between some men dressed in black.
我目睹了一群黑衣人的可疑交易
As I was engrossed in watching them,
当时我只顾着偷看交易
I didn't notice one of them closing up on me from behind.
却忽略了从背后而来的另一个同伙
I was drugged, and when I woke up...
我被灌下了毒药 在我醒来后…
My body shrunk!
我的身体缩小了！
If they knew Shinichi Kudo is still alive,
如果他们知道工藤新一还活着的话
they'd come after me and endanger people around me.
他们会来找我并威胁到我身边的人
Professor Agasa advised me to hide my real identity.
阿笠博士劝我隐瞒自己的真实身份
When Ran asked for my name,
当小兰问起我的名字的时候
I blurted the name Conan Edogawa.
情急之下 我化名为江户川柯南
To get the information on those men in black,
为了获得有关黑衣人的情报
I started living at Ran's place along with her father, a private detective.
我住进了父亲是私人侦探的小兰家中
These are Genta, Mitsuhiko, and Ayumi.
他们是元太 光彦和步美
They are my classmates after I turned small.
他们是我变小后的同班同学
She is Ai Haibara.
她是灰原哀
She was a scientist at the Black Organization
她是黑衣组织的科学家
and she invented the drug that made me small, Apotoxin 4869.
是她发明了APTX4869毒药
However, when her sister was murdered, she rebelled against the organization.
但在她姐姐被人杀害之后她就叛出了组织
As she took the drug in an attempt to end her life,
当她尝试服毒来结束自己生命的时候
her body shrunk.
她的身体缩小了
She now lives at Professor Agasa's place
她现在住在阿笠博士的家
to escape from the eyes of the organization.
以逃过组织的眼线
Within the Black Organization is this man,
这个在黑衣组织里的男人
Tooru Amuro.
安室透
However, his real identity is 'Zero',
他的真实身份是日本公安警察的
an agent of a secret department that commands the Public Security Bureau.
秘密组织专员 代号“零”
His real name is Rei Furuya.
他的真名为降谷零
He works undercover in the Black Organization to gather information.
他潜伏在黑衣组织里搜集情报
He graduated the Police Academy a year before
他毕业于警校
Detective Takagi’s girlfriend, Detective Sato.
好像还有四位淘气的朋友 但…
Hey, Conan!
柯南！
You've said too much!
你话太多了！
You're clearly exposing the plot!
你很显然在剧透！
Just say the line you always do.
说你经常说的那一句就好
O-Oh...
哦哦
Even though my body shrunk, my intelligence remains!
虽然身体变小了 头脑是一样地聪明
The greatest, undefeated detective!
永远不会被打败的名侦探！
There's only one truth!
真相永远只有一个！
Jinpei... Matsuda...
松田阵平
A-Ah...
啊…
I wanted to have a feast at the wedding...
我还想在婚礼上大吃特吃…
I'd never expected it to be a drill!
没想到竟然是一场演习
But Detective Sato was so beautiful!
但佐藤警官真的很漂亮！
A wedding dress is always special to women.
婚纱对女人来说总是特别的
Edogawa seems to be imagining a certain someone in a wedding dress.
江户川好像在想象某人穿婚纱的样子
Wha--
什么
Wow! Who's that someone?
哇！某人是谁啊？
Who is it?
那是谁啊？
Is it Ms. Kobayashi?
是小林老师吗？
What? Why?
什么？为什么？
Anyway, what have you guys been making?
话说回来 你们在做些什么啊？
Cosplay costumes for Halloween!
是万圣节的装扮
We're all going to have fun wearing these!
穿上这些会很有趣
Of course, Conan and Haibara, too!
当然 还有柯南和灰原的！
- What?! - Eh?!
什么？- 诶？
H-Hold on!
等等！
I won't wear something like that--
我也要穿吗…
W-What was that?!
刚刚怎么了？
What is this hole?!
怎么会有一个洞啊？
Ouch...
好痛…
Professor!
博士！
Ah, my bad, my bad. I've startled you.
对不起  吓到你们了
What did you do now?
你这次又做了什么？
This.
是这个
Is that Conan's ball dispensing belt?
这不是柯南的足球腰带吗？
I was trying to reform it so it'd dispense a giant ball, but it didn't go well.
我想改造它来发射一颗巨型球 但进展不太顺利
It's almost done.
差点就完成了
The balance between the surface's elasticity and toughness needs some tuning...
表面的弹性和韧性间的平衡需要做一些调整…
Forget that, I almost got injured falling down here!
重点是我差一点就摔伤了！
Sorry, sorry. Are you alright?
对不起 你没事吧？
I won't forgive you! Treat me to rice with grilled eel!
我不会原谅你的！请我吃烤鳗鱼饭！
I'm afraid I can't agree to that.
不 恐怕我不能答应
There's someone who can treat you right now.
正好有人可以请你吃
Are you kidding me?!
你是在跟我开玩笑吧？
Why do I have to treat these kids?!
我为什么要请这些孩子们吃饭呢？
It's fine to treat them once in a while, isn't it?
偶尔一次没关系吧？
Thank you for the treat!
谢谢你请客！
(Metropolitan Police Department) I only said I'm going to have lunch here
我说我会来这里吃午餐是因为
because I have to come to the MPD to talk about the drill yesterday.
我要去警视厅讨论昨天的演习
Won't lunch be more delicious if we all eat together?
所以大家一起吃不是更美味吗？
I want tempura!
我要天妇罗！
Me, too!
我也是!
Grilled eel for me!
我要烤鳗鱼！
I want rice with grilled eel!
我要烤鳗鱼饭！
Sounds great!
不错哦！
Hey! That's enough!
够了！
Hey.
先生！
You dropped this.
你掉了这个
Haibara!
灰原！
Dad!
爸！
Uncle!
叔叔！
- Haibara! - Uncle! Get a hold of yourself! Uncle!
灰原！- 叔叔！你要撑住！叔叔！
I am alright.
我没事
But...
可是…
Uncle!
叔叔！
Big Sis Ran!
小兰姐姐！
Call the ambulance!
叫救护车！
O-Okay.
是
Watch out!
小心！
Hurry and put it out!
快把火给扑灭！
Darn, I can't get close!
该死 根本无法靠近！
Sure.
好
before it happened, you picked up a note and passed it to him, right?
在那之前 你捡到了一张纸条并交给他了对吧？
Didn't you talk to him then?
你不是跟他说话了吗？
"It's a really important note. I need to give it to someone."
这是我要交给某人的重要纸条
He told me in Russian.
他是用俄语跟我说的
At the very least,
最起码
It doesn't look like an accident or a natural occurrence.
这不像是意外或自然现象
It must've been targeted at the victim.
应该是针对受害者所引发的事故
Hmm, you're right.
你说得对
Looks like a name card.
好像是一张名片
T-That's...
这是…
I've inquired about how the incident happened.
我们了解事情的经过了
What is it?
怎么了？
Look at this.
看看这个
(Sgt. Jinpei Matsuda) T-That's...
这是…
Jinpei Matsuda.
松田阵平
(Jinpei Matsuda) An ex-detective in charge of robbery cases at
警视厅刑事部搜查一课负责抢劫案的前警官
Three years ago, he was transferred to CID 1 due to a certain case.
三年前 他因为某起案件被调往刑事部搜查一课
When he was investigating a serial bombing case,
在调查连环爆炸案的期间
a bomb detonated and he died in the line of duty.
因为炸弹被引爆而因公殉职
'Criminal Investigations Division 1' is written on the card...
名片上写着刑事部搜查一课
He was only in Division 1 for about a week.
他在一课只待了大约一周
Where and when did the victim get this name card?
受害者是在什么时间和地点拿到这张名片的呢？
It's right in front of the MPD, huh?
真的就在前面吗？
A protest against the police?
是针对警察的示威吗？
I'm shocked!
好吓人！
Seriously, they need to leave us out of it!
别牵连到我了
In conclusion,
结论是
the identity of the victim is unknown.
受害者的身份不详
We are currently making a facial composite based on the testimony from the children.
根据孩子们的证词 我们正在进行画像…
We haven't found the note dropped by the victim, have we?
我们还没找到受害人掉的纸条吧？
Looking at the size of the fire,
看那火势
it's likely that the note was lost in the fire.
那纸条很有可能已经被烧毁了
Our only lead at the moment is this name card.
这张名片是我们目前为止唯一的线索
So this is how Matsuda looked like.
松田原来长这样啊
I see.
是啊
Chiba, you were transferred here after Matsuda was killed in the line of duty.
千叶 你是在松田殉职后才被调来这里的
If we cover his eyes, he does look like Takagi.
盖住眼睛的话 长得还真像高木
Yeah.
是啊
When Takagi put on a disguise for a stakeout, he looked exactly like Matsuda.
当高木乔装执行任务的时候他看起来简直跟松田一摸一样
Sorry to keep you waiting.
对不起 让你久等了
For now, we've brought the daily reports for that period.
我们带来了那段时间的新闻报道
Sato, you were in the same group as Matsuda when he was here.
佐藤 在松田生前 你跟他在同一组
Can you think of anything?
你有想起什么吗？
No.
没有
If he'd handed his name card to a foreigner, I would have remembered...
如果他真的把名片给了一名外国人我是不可能想不起来的
Leave the information gathering to the others.
让其他人搜集资料
Please focus on recalling what happened during that time.
请你专心地回想那时候发生过的事
Understood.
我知道了
Did you think I wouldn’t notice?
你觉得我没发现你吗？
Knowing how you always are, you must've been eavesdropping.
你肯定是在偷听
Y-Yes.
是的
Come in.
先进来吧
I don't have to look at these to remember the week I spent with him.
我不需要看这些来回想跟他共事的那一周
Keep this a secret from Takagi.
别告诉高木哦
(Daily Report) He was an amazing detective, wasn't he?
他曾经是一个很棒的警官吧？
Detective Matsuda, I mean.
松田警官
Yes.
是的
He was arrogant and had a sharp tongue.
他很自大还很伶牙俐齿
But...
但是…
If it's okay, can you tell me
如果可以的话 能告诉我吗？
about Detective Matsuda?
有关松田警官的事
Huh?
什么？
While you talk, you might recall something, right?
你可能在说的时候会回想起什么对吧？
Yes...
是…
You're right.
是这样没错
He joined CID 1 three years ago, on November 1.
他是在三年前的十一月一号加入刑事部搜查一课的
I remember because it was the day after Halloween.
我之所以记得是因为前一天是万圣节
But he was transferred here so suddenly, so the name cards were not ready yet.
因为他是突然被调来的所以名片还没准备好
I handed them to him on the morning of November 4.
我是在十一月四号的早上才交给他的
I remember because it was the day after a national holiday.
我会记得这个是因为前一天是公共假期
Matsuda died on November 7.
松田是在十一月七号殉职的
So he could have only handed it out during these four days.
所以他只能是在那四天给出了自己的名片
But we worked in the office on the fourth,
但我们四号一直办事处工作
and on the fifth we only went between the detention center and prison.
而五号我们只往返于拘留所和监狱
On the seventh, we went after the serial bomber until before he passed away.
七号那天我们去追捕连环爆炸案犯人不久后他就殉职了
Which means, he only had the chance to hand out the name card on...
也就是说 他的名片只能是在…
Yes, only on November 6.
对 只能是在十一月六号给的
But there's a possibility that he handed it to someone after work, right?
但他也有可能是在下班后交给了某人 不是吗？
He didn't return to the dormitory for the week he was in our division,
他在我们一课的那一周里并没有回过宿舍
just stayed over at the HQ.
他一直在总部过夜
Thinking about it now,
现在想想
he might have been investigating the serial bombing case.
他可能一直在调查那宗连环爆炸案
But I don't recall anything special happening...
但我想不起来有什么特别的事…
We caught a robber,
我们抓了一名抢劫犯
stopped a bus from going out of control,
成功截停了一辆失控的巴士
and stopped someone from jumping off a building.
还阻止了一起跳楼事件
I think all these happened in the morning?
那都是在早上发生的对吧？
We did some information gathering in the afternoon.
我们下午搜集了情报
(Three Years Ago) What kind of persuasion was that?
你那是什么劝说方式啊？
It's great that she was saved,
还好我们救下了那个人
but I was so afraid she would've been provoked and jumped off.
我还担心她会受到刺激而往下跳
Can you at least listen to me a bit?
你能稍微注意听我说话吗…？
Typing a message?
你在发信息？
You're pretty fast.
好快
I just happen to be good with my fingers.
是的 我的手指比一般人灵活
Is it your girlfriend?
你在给女朋友发信息吧？
Nope. It's for my best friend.
不 在给一个朋友发…
Though I know he's not going to write back to me.
一个即使我发了信息也看不到的好朋友…
He won't read it?
他看不到？
He was blown away four years ago.
他在四年前就被炸死了
What?
什么？
A murder case at Beika third street.
米花第三条街上有一起凶杀案
The culprit is escaping on a bike.
犯人正在骑车逃跑...
Roger that, we will go after him!
了解 我们会前往抓捕！
As I thought, this town isn't ordinary.
这城市果然不一般…
Interrogation for that case ended at about three p.m.
那案子在下午三点就结束审讯了
After that, we returned to Sakuradamon.
之后 我们返回了樱田门
Did Detective Matsuda go through the interrogation together with you?
审讯的时候 松田警官跟你在一起吗？
No, we did it separately...
没有 我们分开行动了…
Sorry to keep you waiting.
对不起 让你久等了
Where did you go?
你去了哪里啊？
It's past six.
已经六点多了
I had something.
我有一些事情
That's...
那是…
What's wrong?
怎么了？
I just remembered, Matsuda had prayer beads in his pocket.
我刚想起来 松田的口袋里有一串念珠
Prayer beads...
念珠…
The person you mentioned earlier, the one Detective Matsuda was texting...
你说松田警官发信息的对象…
Probably it's someone from his year who was in the Explosive Disposal Unit...
很有可能是他在爆炸品处理课的同期…
Kenji Hagiwara.
萩原研二
(Kenji Hagiwara) He was killed
他在七年前拆解炸弹的过程中殉职了
The date of his death was...
他的忌日是…
November 7, same as Matsuda!
十一月七号 跟松田同一天！
The seventh was the day the serial bomber contacted the police.
那名连环爆炸案犯人是在七号那天联络警察的
He was at the HQ until the bomber contacted the police, right?
他在那之前一直都待在总部对吧？
He couldn't visit Hagiwara's grave that day.
也就是说 他那天没办法给荻原扫墓
So he went on the sixth, didn't he?
所以他是六号去的？
If I'm not mistaken, Hagiwara's grave is in a temple near Shibuya.
如果我没记错的话 萩原的墓地应该就在涩谷附近的庙里
Sato, what's wrong?
怎么了 佐藤？
Take care of this!
这个交给你了！
P-Please wait!
请等等我！
Hey, Takagi!
高木！
The interrogation ended at three p.m.
审讯于下午三点结束
Even if he'd gone to visit his friend's grave,
即使他去给自己的同期扫墓了
it still took him too long to be returning after six...
下午六点才回来也太久了吧…
What happened during those three hours?
那三小时里发生了什么…?
Why are you here, Conan?!
你怎么会在这里啊 柯南？
(Getsusan Temple) Ah, yes.
是的
I remember them very well.
我记得他们
Until a few years ago, four of them always came together.
几年前他们四个人一起来过这里
Four of them?
四个人？
(Hagiwara Family Tomb) They said they were Hagiwara's classmates.
他们说他们是萩原的同期
Do you remember the time they came here, three years ago?
你记得他们三年前是什么时候来的吗？
What time were they here?
比如到这里的时间
Every year, they came at about three p.m.
他们每年都准时在下午三点来到这里
But for some reason,
但因为某些原因
the number of people decreased recently, and only one came last year...
来的人变少了 去年只有一个人来了…
It feels quite lonely.
看起来很孤单
Do you know the name of that one person?
你知道那人的名字吗？
If I remember correctly, his name was...
他的名字…
Yes!
对了！
I think his name was Furuya.
他好像是叫降谷
(Metropolitan Police Department Police Academy Graduate List) Rei Furuya...
降谷零…
No matter where I search, this is all I get.
不管我怎么查都只有这个结果
Does this Furuya guy really exist?
降谷真的存在吗？
He was Matsuda's classmate.
他曾经是松田的同期
Even if he'd quit the police force, there should be a record...
就算他退出了警队 也应该有记录的…
Assistant Police Inspector Sato and Police Sergeant Takagi.
佐藤警部补和高木巡查部长
You are...
你是…
Kazami from the Public Security Bureau of Tokyo MPD.
东京都警视厅公安部的风见
May I have a word with you?
我能跟你们谈一谈吗？
Stop the investigation?
停止调查？
The Public Security Bureau will take over this case.
公安部会接手这起案件
What are you talking about?!
你在说什么？
This is under our jurisdiction!
这是我们的管辖区！
You have no say in this.
这不是你能决定的事
This is not a request, but an order.
这不是一个请求 而是命令
This is the end of our conversation.
谈话结束
They can't be serious!
开什么玩笑！
This tyranny is unacceptable!
这种暴政是不能被接受的！
Please calm down!
请冷静点！
This is frustrating, but we can't do anything.
虽然很不甘心 但我们什么也做不了
I am calm!
我很冷静！
Don't spout nonsense!
别乱说
B-But...
但是…
I'm going to negotiate!
我要跟上头谈判！
U-Uh...
什么
Sato!
佐藤！
She got so worked up, because...
她之所以这么激动是因为…
It involves Matsuda, and she can't keep her cool.
这件事涉及到松田 所以她没办法保持冷静
Shiratori!
白鸟！
That's quite an expression on your face.
你这是什么表情啊
Y-Yeah…
我…
She hasn't been aware of anything around her
她自从看到松田的名片
ever since she saw Matsuda's name card...
就表现得很冲动…
Shiratori, you said this before...
白鸟 你说过…
If she's still preoccupied about her past with Matsuda,
只要她还想着和松田的过去
we have no chance to win.
我们就根本说服不了她
I did. But I was wrong.
是 但不全对
The one with no chance to win is me.
说服不了她的人是我
Am I wrong?
不是吗？
A-Ah...
啊…
But I'm still not good enough...
但我还是有很多不足的地方...
But you have advanced a fair bit.
你已经有进步了
A-Advanced?
进步？
You're jealous of
你嫉妒一名冒着生命危险挽救无数性命的传奇警官
No, I am not jealous...
不 我才没有嫉妒他…
It doesn't matter if it involves Matsuda.
不管有没有涉及到松田
If our case was stolen, we just have to take it back.
只要我们的案子被抢了 我们就得把它给拿回来
Hurry up, or else Sato will be yelling at the Public Security by herself.
快去吧 不然佐藤就得一个人面对公安部了
Excuse me.
失陪了
Thank you very much!
谢谢你
Well, I felt quite obligated because I did disrupt your romance...
毕竟我妨碍你谈恋爱了…
Ah, Ms. Kobayashi!
小林老师！
He doesn't have a bone fracture,
他没有骨折
but he suffered a strong blow on his head.
但头部受到了重创
He needs to undergo a thorough check-up after moving to another hospital tomorrow.
他需要在明天转院后接受全身检查
Uncle...
叔叔…
Coming.
来了
May I know who is this?
请问你们是谁？
(Tsutomu Muranaka Christine Richard) My name is Tsutomu Muranaka.
我是村中努
This is my fiancée...
这是我的未婚妻…
My name is Christine Richard.
我叫克里斯汀·理查德
Mr. Muranaka and Ms. Christine...
村中先生和克里斯汀小姐…
Ah, from the drill yesterday!
啊 昨天的演习！
I didn't know Megure did that.
我不知道目暮安排了那个…
Apologies for troubling everyone.
对不起 麻烦你们了
Not at all, please don't mention it.
不麻烦 请别这么说
I'm just a little surprised...
我只是有点惊讶…
I'd like to apologize as well.
我也很抱歉
It's alright.
别在意
Ah, your Japanese is fluent!
你的日语说得真好！
Both of my parents are French, but I've been living in Japan since I was 20.
我父母都是法国人但我从二十岁就住在日本了
I met her at the hospital.
我是在医院遇到她的
When I was hospitalized for an injured shoulder.
我因为肩膀受伤而入院
I was troubled because I lost my patient ID card, and he found it for me.
我因为弄丢了住院证件而不知所措 但他帮我找到了
It was a fateful encounter!
那还真是命中注定！
Well, something like that.
是那样没错
Why are you here today?
你们怎么会来呢？
Actually, I asked Detective Mouri to give a speech at our wedding.
我其实邀请了毛利侦探到我们的婚礼上发表演讲
Both of us are huge fans of the Sleeping Kogoro.
我们都是沉睡的小五郎的忠实粉丝
I see!
原来如此！
I can't let this go.
这真是无法原谅
To think they targeted Detective Mouri.
他们竟然这么对毛利侦探
I don't think they were going after my father.
不 我不觉得我爸是他们的攻击目标
He was just protecting a child from the explosion...
他只是在爆炸现场救了一个孩子...
What?
什么？
The child picked up something that the victim had dropped,
那孩子捡到了受害者掉的东西
and just as she handed it over, the victim burst up in flames.
她才刚递过去 那人就被炸死了
My father tried to help her and...
我爸试着救她…
Sleeping Kogoro is a hero who saved the child.
沉睡的小五郎是救了那孩子的英雄
That's right.
是啊
Sorry to come uninvited during such a difficult time.
很抱歉在这种时候不请自来
When he's awake, please send our regards to Detective Mouri.
请在毛利侦探醒来后替我向他问好
Of course.
没问题
Thank you very much.
谢谢光顾
Speaking of which, the wedding venue is gorgeous!
话说回来 结婚场地真的很漂亮
Isn't it?
是吧？
It gives a panoramic view of Shibuya, so I chose it at first sight.
整个涩谷都尽收眼底我一眼就选定它了
Ah... The weather was bad yesterday...
啊… 昨天的天气不好…
It was foggy, so we didn't get a clear view.
起雾了所以我们没看清楚
Then, would you like to check out the venue tomorrow?
那你们要不要明天去看看场地呢？
Hey, Detective Mouri is like this...
毛利侦探还在医院…
But... It's such a pity if we don't get to see the beautiful Halloween decorations.
但是… 没看到美丽的万圣节装饰就太可惜了
Please?
可以吗？
Well,
好吧
if you put it that way...
既然你都这样说了…
Thank you very much!
谢谢你！
Well, see you tomorrow.
那明天见
I heard from Dad that
我听爸爸说…
Mr. Muranaka was a really strict person so
村中先生是一个很严肃的人
he was feared as the Demon Muranaka.
大家都叫他魔鬼村中
Is that so?
是吗？
It's hard to imagine that from the Mr. Muranaka we met.
很难想象我们见到的村中先生是那样
I'm sure that Ms. Christine has changed him into a gentle person.
我想一定是克里斯汀小姐让他变温柔了
It's getting late...
已经这么晚了…
I think it's time for us to head home.
我想我们该回家了
Big Sis Ran,
小兰姐姐
I'll be staying over at Professor Agasa’s place,
我会去阿笠博士那里过夜
so you can stay here with Uncle.
所以你可以留在这里陪着叔叔
But...
但是…
Don't worry, I'll be fine by myself.
别担心 我一个人可以的
Thank you.
谢谢你
Take care, then.
那你小心一点
Okay.
好
You're there, aren't you?
你们在的吧？
Anything you need from me?
有什么需要我的地方吗？
Great work.
辛苦了
I-I'll help out as well.
我也来帮忙
You don't have to force yourself.
你不需要勉强自己
I'm not forcing myself.
我没在勉强自己
The Grim Reaper...
死神…
What?
什么？
Just like the serial bombing case,
跟连环爆炸案那个时候一样
the Grim Reaper appeared again...
死神又出现了…
That's why, you might be right.
所以你说得对
I might've been too hot-headed recently.
我最近可能太鲁莽了
I'm sorry.
对不起
Sato...
佐藤…
If I'm going to be caught up with such thoughts,
如果我再这样纠结下去
I might as well quit being a police and marry you.
我还不如辞职嫁给你算了…
Just kidding!
开玩笑的！
Please don't say something so depressing.
请不要说这么泄气的话
What?
什么？
If a police officer gives up on investigating a case,
如果一个警察放弃调查案件
and quit their job, doesn't that mean they're defeated?
还辞职了 那不就意味着他认输了吗？
Takagi...
高木…
I don't want to see you defeated.
我不要看到泄气的你
Because I love and yearn for
因为我爱的是
the police officer, Miwako Sato!
佐藤美和子警官！
Y-You're right,
你说得对
Wataru...
涉…
But...
但是…
That's a separate matter...
这是两回事…
Y-You know, about...
跟…
Marrying me...
嫁给我…
She's gone!
她不见了！
Get off.
下车
What's your plan for bringing me here,
你带我来这里想干什么呢？
Amuro?
安室？
You already knew, eh?
果然 你早就知道了？
I've heard about the order to stop investigating
因为我听说了要停止调查…
the foreigner immolation case that took place in front of the MPD.
那外国人在警视厅前的自焚案
The ones who could do something like that are either people with a big influence, or...
能下这样的命令的人要么有很大的权利要么就只能是…
The Public Security Bureau.
公安部
This case is related to Detective Matsuda who died in the line of duty,
这案子涉及到因公殉职的松田警官
and you were in the same year as him back in the Police Academy.
而你跟他是警校的同期
That’s also when Detective Takagi and Detective Sato
而且刑事部搜查一课的高木警官
from CID 1 began investigating this case.
和佐藤警官才刚开始调查这起案件
Once I consider that information, the answer is clear.
考虑到这些 答案就出来了
You've already known so much and purposely isolated yourself
你已经知道了这么多 还故意落单
to create the chance for us to restrain you...
制造机会让我们把你给带走…
Who are you?
你到底是谁?
That's not important. What kind of facility is this?
话说回来这是什么地方啊？
This is an underground shelter that belongs to the PSB.
这是隶属公安部的地下室
This special tempered glass separates us.
我们之间隔着特制的钢化玻璃
It even intercepts electromagnetic waves.
它甚至可以拦截电磁波
If a huge explosion was to occur here, you could walk away unscathed,
如果这里发生了大爆炸你可以毫发无损地离开
and no one above would notice any difference.
上面没有人会察觉到任何异样
That collar-like thing around your neck...
你脖子上那个像项圈的东西…
Yes, it's a bomb.
是的 是个炸弹
We have no idea if it's a time bomb or controlled remotely.
我们不知道它是定时炸弹还是远程操控的
No idea how to defuse it, either.
也不知道该怎么拆解
It's frustrating, but we don't know what to do.
这很令人沮丧 但我们不知道能怎么办
I know the detectives from Division 1 are searching for me.
我知道一课的警官都在找我
But I can't possibly meet them in this state, can I?
但我不可能在这种状态下跟他们见面 不是吗？
Also...
而且…
If they find out your identity, your undercover investigation would go to waste.
如果他们知道了你的身份你的卧底调查就会前功尽弃
I'll have to quit working part-time at Café Poirot, too.
我也需要辞掉在波洛咖啡厅的兼职工作
And that's why you brought me here.
所以你才把我带来了这里
I'll tell you about everything I know.
我会告诉你所有我知道的事
Please help the detectives with their investigation.
请帮助一课的警官们进行调查
So, on November 6 three years ago,
所以 在三年前的十一月六号
you met Detective Matsuda?
你见到了松田警官吧？
Yes, I did.
是的
It'd been a long time since the four of us met.
我很久没见到我的四名同期了…
Hey...
真是的…
You're late.
你迟到了
I thought you weren't coming, Matsuda.
我以为你不会来了 松田
Sorry.
不好意思
One case after another Couldn't find a chance to leave.
案件一起接着一起我找不到机会离开
You moved to Division 1, right?
你被调去了一课吧？
How do you find it?
感觉如何？
Well, it is okay.
还好吧
I'll be working at the MPD starting next month.
我下个月开始会在警视厅上班
Don't fail at your job and get chased out, Senior!
可别懈怠然后被赶出去了 前辈！
Idiot, you were a detective before me.
笨蛋 你比我更早成为警察
Hagiwara would be happy to see you.
萩原会很高兴见到你的
There's no way I'm not coming.
我不可能不来
My promise to avenge him…
我还没兑现…
hasn't been realized yet.
我要替他复仇的承诺
To think something like that happened the next day...
没想到第二天就发生了那样的事…
That's not the end of it, right?
这还没有结束吧？
Didn't something happen after that?
那之后又发生了什么吧？
Something related to the explosion case.
与爆炸案有关的事
Why do you think so?
你为什么会这么想呢？
I did a little research.
我做了一些调查
The grave is in a temple near Shibuya.
墓地在涩谷附近的一座寺庙里
On that day three years ago, there was a gas leak at a multipurpose building.
在三年前的同一天 有一栋综合体建筑发生了煤气泄漏事件
Exactly like what you've deduced.
正如你所推理的一样
That day...
那一天…
Drop me off at Shibuya Station.
放我在涩谷站下来
I'll head home by myself.
我自己回家
Sorry, but I can only drop you off near the station.
对不起 我只能送你到车站附近
I almost forgot. Just like Morofushi,
我差点忘了 你跟诸伏情况差不多
you can't attract attention.
你们都得保持低调…
Mr. Police, seems like it's time to work.
看来你又要开始忙了 警官
Sheesh, what a day!
真是的！
Matsuda and I went there and were told that
我和松田到了之后得知
someone snuck into the abandoned building
有人潜入了废弃大楼里
and was going on a rampage.
然后开始闹事
I asked for help from the others who were with us at the temple.
我叫了跟我们一起去庙里的其他人帮忙
Before they arrived at the scene,
在他们抵达现场之前
Matsuda and I went in first to check the situation.
我和松田先进去查看情况
Looks like he's unconscious.
看来他已经昏过去了
Doesn't look Japanese.
他看起来不像是日本人
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
Calm down.
保持冷静
We're the police.
我们是警察
Police.
警察
Can you understand?
听得懂吗？
Run!
跑！
Hmm?
嗯？
That's Russian, he's telling us to run.
是俄语 他让我们快跑
Go on ahead.
先下去
If the police stops you, show them this name card.
如果有警察拦你 就把这张名片递给他们
If the police stops you, show them this name card.
如果警察拦你 就把这张名片递给他们
Seems like we have another guest here.
看来这里还有别人
I'm outta here!
我先跑了！
You're well-prepared. As expected of a Public Security Officer.
你已经准备好了不愧是公安部警官
Don't move!
别动！
This is bad...
大事不妙…
What?
怎么了?
There's a bomb behind him.
他身后的东西是颗炸弹
If we accidentally hit it, it might go 'boom'.
不小心打到了就会爆炸
Looking at its size,
看它的大小
if it explodes, everyone in this building will die.
所有这栋楼里的人都会被它送上西天
Can you defuse it?
你能拆解吗？
You think I can't?
你觉得我拆解不了吗？
I'll leave it to you.
拜托你了
Hold on!
别跑！
I'll go after him.
我去追他
Matsuda, hurry and defuse the bomb!
松田 你快去拆弹！
Yeah.
好
I'll leave them to you, too.
那我就把他交给你了
They went downstairs...
他下楼了…
Damn! They're going after Matsuda!
糟了 他要去找松田！
Damn it.
该死
Don't disrupt my fun bomb-defusing time!
别打扰我拆弹的快乐时光！
Leader!
班长！
Don't taunt the guy with gun in his hand!
别激怒手里拿着枪的家伙！
Hiro!
景光！
Is Zero alright?
零没事吧？
Thank you, you saved us!
谢谢你救了我们！
It was a great idea to take the car door that he broke.
拿走他打坏的车门可真是个好主意
Wait!
别跑！
Darn!
该死！
Both of you, move aside!
你们给我让开！
I won't let you escape.
我不会让你逃脱的
Leader!
班长！
Please!
拜托你了！
Are you serious?!
真的假的？
That's so reckless...
太鲁莽了…
Hiro! Leader!
景光！班长！
Their accomplice might still be hiding somewhere.
他的同伙可能还躲在某个地方
I'll leave Matsuda to you!
我把松田交给你了！
O-Okay.
好
Be careful!
你要当心！
Yeah!
好！
Leader, I'll cover Zero.
班长 我去掩护零
They're not an ordinary person.
那人可不是一般人
It might be tough to face him alone.
一个人对付他会很困难
Yeah, I'll leave it to you!
好 那就交给你了！
Yeah.
好
A grenade!
手榴弹！
He's still trying to escape?
他还想逃走吗？
He might still have an accomplice.
他可能还有同伙
There's none.
没有
Hmm?
嗯？
If there were any, he wouldn't have returned to kill me.
如果有 他不会回来杀我
Y-Yeah, you're right.
你说得对
Leader, do you have chewing gum?
班长 你有口香糖吗？
Chewing helps me concentrate.
口香糖能帮我集中精神
Every single one of you...
你们一个两个的…
I'm no longer the squad leader.
我已经不是班长了…
Zero, are you hurt?
零 你没事吧？
H-Hiro...
景光…
Darn!
该死！
Hiro, wait!
景光 等一下！
He's wounded, leave it to the reinforcements.
他受伤了 我们把他交给支持队伍吧
Zero, are you alright?
零 你没事吧？
Yeah. You saved me, Hiro.
我没事 是你救了我
Shaking or tilting it ever so slightly,
即使轻微晃动或倾斜
and the liquid would flow out, causing an explosion.
里面的液体也可能会流出并引起爆炸
I'm sorry, he escaped.
对不起 让他逃走了
Woah! Are you alright, Zero?
你没事吧 零？
Nothing to worry about.
我没事
How is it going?
情况如何？
The situation here isn't great, either.
这里的情况也好不了多少
Leave this to me and go evacuate the civilians nearby.
把这里交给我然后去疏散附近的居民
B-But...
但是…
Just go. There's only three minutes left.
去吧 只剩下三分钟了
Make up some excuse, just say that there's a gas leak and evacuate people.
编造一个理由 就说有煤气泄漏 要疏散民众
Understood.
我知道了
Let's go, Hiro.
我们走吧 景光
Leader, you, too.
你也走吧 班长
Fine.
我知道了
Matsuda...
松田…
We will be
我们会在…
waiting for you outside.
外面等你
I can't make the promise.
我可答应不了你
Get away from here, now!
现在马上离开这里！
That was close...
好险…
Wha--
什么？
Remotely triggered? Darn!
远程操控吗？该死！
What would Hagi do in this situation?
萩原在这个时候会怎么做呢？
If I were him...
如果我是他…
Jinpei!
阵平！
Phone!
电话！
That was terrifying.
太吓人了
I suddenly recalled what you once did.
我突然想起了你以前做过的事
Was that to thank me for visiting your grave?
是为了感谢我去探望你了吗？
In other words, the victim was the same person from back then...
也就是说 受害者是同一个人…
But I don't know who that man was.
但我不知道那人是谁
That incident wasn't reported anywhere, right?
那件事没有任何报道吧？
It was announced as a gas leak incident.
那件事被报道为一场煤气泄漏事件
Public Security intervened and all info was sealed off by the upper level.
公安插手然后警部高层封锁了所有消息
(Warehouse Explosion) Is this...
这是…
I had to let you know that.
我需要让你知道
As you see, I am not in a situation to be moving around.
你知道我不能戴着炸弹四处走动
All the best.
祝你好运
Whoa! Amazing!
哇！好美啊！
When we were here before,
我们之前来这里的时候
the weather was bad, so we didn't get a clear view.
天气差到都看不清楚景色
Ah, over there!
啊 那里！
I see a store selling something delicious!
我看到一间卖好吃食物的店！
Where is it?
哪里？
Sorry for all the noise...
对不起 吵到你们了…
It's nice to be lively.
热闹是好事
Anyway, how is Detective Mouri doing?
话说回来 毛利侦探怎么样了？
He's regained consciousness and was transferred to a hospital nearby.
他恢复了意识已经被转到了附近的医院
(Shibuya Central Hospital) O-Ouch!
痛死我了！
Do something!
做些什么吧！
This is strange.
真奇怪
The anesthetic should be working.
麻醉药应该已经起了作用的
Does he have tolerance to anesthetic?
他对麻醉有抗药性吗？
His painkiller wore off and he was making a fuss like a child.
他止痛药的药效过了所以像个孩子一样在胡闹
Look at that!
看那边！
The helicopter is so close!
直升机好靠近哦！
There's a heliport on the rooftop of this building, the Hikarie.
这栋Hikarie的屋顶上有一个停机坪
We plan to go around Tokyo in a helicopter after the wedding.
我们打算在婚礼结束后搭上直升机绕东京一圈
That's lovely!
那好棒！
How romantic!
好浪漫呢！
Excuse me.
不好意思
Yes, what is it?
是 什么事？
Yes.
是…
What?
什么？
Uhm, after this, I have a meeting...
我等一下还要开会…
Hello?
喂？
What happened?
怎么了？
A friend has something she has to give me, and since she's in Shibuya,
一个朋友有东西要给我
she wants me to come over.
她在涩谷 所以让我去找她
That's a problem.
这还真麻烦啊
We have a meeting with the emcee after this...
我们之后还要和婚礼司仪开会…
I told her that...
我跟她说了…
Shall we make the trip for you?
要不我们帮你去拿吧？
Eh?
什么？
It's nearby, right?
就在这附近 不是吗？
But...
但是…
Leave it to us!
交给我们吧！
Don't underestimate us just because we're kids!
别因为我们是孩子就小看我们！
We accept any request!
我们可以接受任何委托！
We're the best first-graders!
我们是最棒的一年级生！
Here come the Junior Detectives!
少年侦探团来了！
When did it become 'the best’?
什么时候变成最棒的了？
In that case, can I leave this to you?
那我能拜托你们吗？
I just received the map via text, so let me draw it out for you.
我刚通过电子邮件收到了地图 让我画给你们看
Okay!
好！
Sorry for the hassle.
麻烦你们了
Will you kids be alright?
你们没有问题吧？
I'd love to come along with you but I need to go back to the hospital.
我想和你们一起去 但我需要赶回医院
This is a piece of cake!
这是小事一桩！
Here, this is the map.
来 地图在这里
Thank you very much!
谢谢！
Conan, you too...
柯南你也…
Where are you going?
你们要去哪里啊？
Conan? Ai?
柯南？小哀？
This is the place.
我们到了
T-This is different from what I've imagined...
这地方和我想象的不一样...
But it can't be wrong.
但不会有错的
It's here, on the sixth floor...
是这里的六楼…
Let's just go.
我们走吧
Okay...
好…
It's here…
是这里…
Excuse me...
不好意思…
We are here on behalf of Ms. Christine to receive the present...
我们是替克里斯汀小姐来这里拿礼物的…
Is anyone here?
有人在吗?
There's no sign of anyone...
这里好像没有人…
The present is covered by a piece of cloth...
礼物是被一块布盖着…
Could that be the present?
那个会是礼物吗？
It's huge...
好大…
I’ll go.
我去吧
All of you, wait here.
你们在这里等着
Be careful...
小心点…
That's the present?
这就是礼物吗？
What's that?
这是什么？
This is...
这是…
It's a bomb!! Get away, quick!
是炸弹！快离开这里！
The door closed on its own?!
这门自动关上了？
We've been had!
我们被骗了！- 我们开不了门！
It's a trap!
这根本就是个陷阱！- 我们开不了门
Less than two minutes until it explodes!
离爆炸只剩不到两分钟了！
I'll find a way, you guys get out of here first!
我会想办法逃脱
B-But...
但是…
Just go, quick!
快走吧！
Let's go.
我们走
A-Are we going to leave Conan behind?!
我们要丢下柯南吗？
Right now, we can only trust Edogawa.
我们现在也只能相信江户川了
Hurry up!
快！
There isn't much time!
没时间了！
Darn!
该死！
Conan, you have to get out safely!
柯南 你一定要安全离开！
Yeah!
好！
I can possibly go down this pipe and...
我可以沿着这条水管滑下去…
This bomb's structure is almost identical.
炸弹的结构几乎一样
Would this work...?
这能行吗…?
What's going on here?!
这是怎么一回事啊?
Edogawa...
江户川…
What?!
什么?
Something fell.
有东西掉下来了
What's this?
这是什么?
Everyone!
大家!
Lend me hand!
帮帮我!
Conan!
柯南!
What's going on?!
这是要做什么啊?
A kettle?
热水壶?
Give me that!
用那个做些什么！
What?
什么?
He needs the cloth!
他需要那块布!
I see, that's what he meant!
原来是这样!
Edogawa!
江户川!
Come as low as possible!
尽可能慢慢地滑下来！
We can't help if you fall from that height!
你从高处掉下来的话 我们是帮不了你的！
Yeah!
我知道！
Hurry up!
快点！
It's going to explode soon!
它要爆炸了！
I know!
我知道！
Quick!
快！
Conan!
柯南！
Don't take your sweet time!
别磨蹭了！
Idiot!
笨蛋！
Edogawa!
江户川！
It's hot!
好烫！
Conan!
柯南！
Here!
这里！
Wait! This way!
等等 这里！
Ouch!
好痛！
Are you alright?
你没事吧！
Yea, I'm fine.
我没事
Thank you.
谢谢你们
Let's get away, quick!
我们快点离开这里！
Y-Yes!
好！
That was dangerous!
好险！
That was so close!
就差一点！
I'm so glad you're alright, Conan!
还好你没事 柯南！
Conan! Everyone!
柯南！孩子们！
Big Sis Ran!
小兰姐姐！
Are you injured?
你们受伤了吗？
Is everyone fine?
大家都没事吧？
Yes, somehow.
我们都没事
Is it true that there was a bomb?!
是真的有炸弹吗？
Yeah!
是的！
I saw it with my own eyes!
我亲眼看见的！
It was glowing creepily, it was scary!
它闪着奇怪的光 很恐怖！
- And the cloth... - Conan was locked in the room...
他拉开那块布后 出现了奇怪的装置- 柯南被锁在房里了…
Wait, don’t speak at the same time.
等等 别同时说
I'll ask you one by one...
我会一个一个问你们…
Can you analyze the content of the kettle and the liquid on my jacket?
你能分析一下热水壶里的东西和我夹克上的液体吗？
(Shibuya Central Police Station) Thank goodness you're all fine.
还好你们都没事
When I heard that the building that caught fire is the one you were heading to,
当我听说起火的建筑就是你们去的地方 我脸都吓白了
It was terrifying, but I climbed down using the drainage pipe.
是很可怕 但我顺着排水管滑了下来
Wow, that's impressive.
你真棒
You're more courageous than me.
你比我还勇敢
Ms. Christine, we are all safe now.
克里斯汀小姐 我们现在都没事了
Please don't blame yourself.
请别自责
Thank you...
谢谢你…
According to Conan,
据柯南说
the time bomb was suddenly triggered and the room's door was shut close.
定时炸弹是突然被启动的房门也随后被锁上
Seems like they wanted to be sure they got rid of whoever that went in.
看来他们是想确保能杀死进入房间的人
That's why I want to ask, who contacted Ms. Christine?
是谁打给克里斯汀小姐的呢？
I tried to check, but my friend said
我试着查过了
that she doesn't remember making such a call...
但我完全想不起来接过这个电话…
I'll go search the surrounding area for witnesses.
我会去四周寻找目击证人
Someone could have witnessed the person who planted the bomb there.
可能会有目击者看到在那里安置炸弹的人
You don't have to.
就不劳烦你了
Chiba is already on it.
千叶已经在找了
It happened in Shibuya,
虽然是在涩谷
but not many people pass by this area...
但经过这一带的人并不多…
I guess there's little hope of finding a witness.
我想找到目击者的希望不大
Hey, is everything alright?
你没事吧？
Wha--
啊
What are you doing?!
你想干什么啊？
Ah, I see...
啊 这样啊...
Let me know once you find out more.
有其它线索再联络我
Megure.
目暮
I'm sorry, but can we leave now?
抱歉 我们能离开了吗？
She's quite stressed out.
她挺焦虑的
I'm sorry about that.
真不好意思
You are allowed to leave.
你们可以回去了
Okay...
好…
The bomb planted there...
安置在那里的炸弹…
It's quite similar to the bomb
跟三年前安室和他朋友
Amuro and his friends defused three years ago.
拆解的炸弹很相似
It's said that a bomb reflects the personality of its maker.
据说炸弹会反映出制造者的个性- 再见
Thank you for your time.
据说炸弹会反映出制造者的个性- 谢谢你的配合
So it's very likely that the same culprit is responsible for both cases...
所以两起案件很有可能是同一犯人所为…
She might need psychological support...
她可能需要一些心理辅导…
Indeed...
是啊…
It's Chiba.
是千叶
Hello?
喂？
I'll say it once more.
我再说一次
We have taken Detective Chiba.
我们带走了千叶警官
If you want him back unscathed,
如果你要他毫发无损地回去
bring Detective Jinpei Matsuda here.
就把松田阵平警官带来这里
Detective Matsuda?!
松田警官？
What are you after?
你有什么目的？
Is Chiba safe?!
千叶没事吧？
We'll contact you again.
我们会再联络你的
They told us to bring Matsuda, but...
他们让我们把松田带过去 但…
What are they after?
犯人有什么目的？
Why are they asking for Matsuda now?
为什么他们要找松田呢…
(Bombing at the giant ferris wheel in Taito Mall) In that bombing incident,
那一次爆炸事件
(One police officer killed dismantling the bomb.) a police officer was reported to have died in the line of duty,
虽然报道了一名警官因公殉职
but Detective Matsuda's name was not made public...
但却没有公布松田警官的名字…
Instead, if they find out he's passed away...
如果他们发现他已经去世了的话…
What should we do?
我们该怎么办？
If this goes on, Chiba's life is in danger...
照这样下去 千叶会有生命危险…
Um...
那个…
I have an idea...
我有个想法…
I definitely did not foresee an officer from Division 1 to be abducted.
我真没想到他们会把一课的警官给掳走
This was taken by that young boy, Conan.
这是那个叫柯南的少年拍的照片
Judging from this, it's extremely similar to the bomb from three years ago.
由此看来 这与三年前的炸弹极为相似
So it's the same culprit...
所以是同一名犯人…
Have you received information on that person?
你收到那个人的资料了吗？
The upper level reluctantly budged.
高层很不乐意帮忙
I just received it.
我才刚收到
What about the liquid explosive that Conan collected?
柯南收集的液体炸药呢？
We're analyzing it right now.
我们正在分析它
Once complete, we'll produce the neutralizer.
分析完成后 我们会生产中和剂
He risked his life to collect those samples.
那是他冒着生命危险收集到的样本
We cannot let it go to waste.
我们不能让他白费功夫
What should we do next?
我们接下来该怎么做？
Assist Division 1 in rescuing the abducted officer.
协助一课营救被掳走的警官
You may reveal all the information we possess.
你可以向他们透露我们已掌握的所有信息
Understood.
我知道了
In the meantime, we've done everything we could.
我们已经做了我们能做的一切
So...
那么…
What is your next move?
你下一步会怎么做呢？
Seriously?!
你是认真的吗？
That's too risky!
这太危险了！
We are aware of the risks.
我们知道那很危险
But there'll be a hidden mic and a transmitter attached.
但我们会用隐藏的麦克风和传感器
If anything happens, we'll be there immediately--
如果有什么事情 我们能立即赶到
What if we can't make it there in time?!
如果来不及呢？
If the same thing as three years ago happens--
如果发生了和三年前一样的事情
Sato!
佐藤！
It'll be fine.
我不会有事的
I seem to have the devil's luck.
我运气很好的
The only person who can save Chiba right now…
现在唯一能救千叶的人…
is none other than me.
也只有我了
Kazami from Public Security Bureau just offered to assist this investigation.
公安部的风见刚刚提出要协助这一次的调查
From now on, we'll work together with PSB.
从现在起 我们会和公安部联手
We'll rescue Chiba by any means necessary!
我们会不顾一切地救出千叶！
Yes, let's go!
是的 我们出发吧！
I definitely won’t let you die.
我绝对不会让你死掉
Hey, Detective Sato…
佐藤警官…
Is this evidence from the bombing incident
这是发生在警视厅门前的
in front of the MPD?
爆炸案的证物吗？
Yes, it is.
是的 没错
Apparently, they found it in the shrubbery.
他们在灌木丛中找到了它
Seems like it's some kind of note.
似乎是某种笔记
He said, "It's a really important note. I need to give it to someone."
他说那是他要交给某人的重要纸条…
This is...
这是…
The message that he wanted to show Detective Matsuda?
他要给松田警官的纸条吗？
I made the call, Detective Matsuda will be here soon.
我打了电话 松田警官
Are you sure this is going to work out?
你确定这能成功吗？
We have no other way to draw Plamya out.
我们也没有其他办法能引出普拉米亚了
If they refuse, this man is finished.
如果他们拒绝 这个人就完了
We'd like to avoid that.
我们要尽量避免这种情况
(Shibuya Central Police Station) So, what's the point
把我们所有人召集到这里的目的是什么？
Sharing information.
共享情报
Oh? You're going to let us meet that Furuya person?
是吗？你打算让我们见见降谷吗？
I can't do that.
我不能那么做
He's being quarantined at a separate facility,
他正在一个独立的设施里隔离
as he has a bomb attached to his neck.
因为他脖子上戴着一颗炸弹
A few days ago, the serial bomber that you've caught escaped using some trick.
你们几天前抓到的那个连环爆炸案犯人设法逃跑了
When Furuya was going after that man,
降谷在追捕这个人的时候
he was assaulted by somebody and got a choker-shaped bomb around his neck.
被某人袭击然后在他脖子上装了一颗项圈形状的炸弹
Then, what about the man who escaped?
那逃脱的人呢？
A bomb, the same model that was later attached to Furuya,
他被和戴在降谷身上的同一类型的炸弹给炸死了
It can't be...
什么…
We believe this series of action was a trap
我们相信这一系列行为是某人设下的陷阱
to lure Furuya out.
目的是引出降谷
After analyzing it,
经过分析
we found out that the choker-shaped bomb uses
我们发现那个项圈炸弹用了两种混合在一起就会引爆的液体炸药
It's the same type of bomb used in the incident three years ago.
这跟三年前的爆炸案里用的是同一种炸弹
Hmm... Then, who is he indeed?
那他到底是谁？
You guys stopped him, right?
你们阻止了他对吧？
An assassin, real identity unknown.
凶手的真实身份不详
Nationality, gender, and age, are all unknown.
国籍 性别和年龄也未知
They work all over the world, but is based in Russia.
他在全球范围内都很活跃 但总部设在俄罗斯
Also known and feared as 'Plamya'.
他被称为“普拉米亚”
Hey, in Russian, 'Plamya' means fire, right?
“普拉米亚”在俄语里是火的意思吧？
What is it like when the explosives detonate?
炸弹被引爆后是什么样子的？
Did you bring this young boy here?
是你把这少年带到这里的吗？
He witnessed the strange bomb explode twice,
他目睹了两次爆炸
I thought it'd speed things up if he was here.
我想如果他在的话 能更快地理出头绪
So, what's the bomb like?
所以那炸弹是怎么样的呢？
It has both strong combustibility and explosiveness.
它兼具强大的可燃性和爆炸性
The instant the liquids come into contact, it explodes, and the flame spreads.
两种液体一旦接触就会爆炸并让火势蔓延
That's similar to what we saw happen to the foreigner.
就跟我们在那个外国人身上看到的情况相似
The one killed in front of the MPD?
在警视厅门前被杀的那个人吗？
Yes.
是的
Why go through the hassle to do it in front of the MPD?
为什么犯人要特意在警视厅前那么做呢？
And the reason why the victim visited the MPD remains a mystery.
话说回来 受害者前往警视厅的原因依然成谜
The hint lies in the name card, doesn't it?
提示就在名片上 不是吗？
Matsuda?
松田？
The foreigner came to meet Detective Matsuda, didn't he?
那外国人是要去找松田警官 不是吗？
Even if there was a risk, he still needed Detective Matsuda's cooperation.
即使有风险他仍然需要松田警官的配合
In other words...
也就是说…
The victim and the culprit who kidnapped Chiba...
受害者和绑架千叶的犯人…
Are related to one another?
是有关联的？
Mmhm.
嗯
Regarding the explosion at the multipurpose building today,
关于今天在综合体建筑里发生的爆炸案
there is a high possibility that Plamya's special bomb was used.
很有可能使用了普拉米亚的特殊炸弹
Conan and the Junior Detectives showing up was beyond Plamya's expectations.
他没预料到柯南和少年侦探团会出现在那里
The real target was Muranaka and his wife…
他真正的目标是村中和他的妻子…
Muranaka received a threat for his wedding.
村中收到了婚礼的恐吓
Plamya's targets are definitely Muranaka and his wife...
普拉米亚的目标绝对是村中和他的妻子…
However...
但是…
The relationship between the foreigner immolation case
我们还没搞清楚外国人自焚案和千叶被绑架的关联性
Also, since Plamya had information regarding the person named Furuya,
还有 既然普拉米亚掌握了关于降谷这个人的情报
I think he must have known about Detective Matsuda dying in the line of duty.
我想他一定也知道松田警官因公殉职了…
Hey, among Furuya's classmates at Police Academy,
那个叫降谷的人的同期
four have died, right?
有四人都死了吧？
Detective Matsuda and Hagiwara from the Explosive Disposal Unit,
爆炸品处理课的松田和萩原警官
while defusing bombs.
在拆解炸弹时殉职
Detective Date, in a traffic accident.
伊达警官死于一场交通事故
What about Morofushi?
那么那么叫诸伏的人呢？
Morofushi?
诸伏？
I'm sorry, but that is top secret.
对不起 那是最高机密
As usual, you're secretive.
你还是像往常一样神秘
I can say this much.
我只能说这么多
It has nothing to do with this case.
他跟这个案子毫无关系
Are you asking us to believe you?
你是要我们相信你吗？
Well, hold on.
等等
Our priority now is to save Chiba.
我们目前的首要任务是营救千叶
Takagi, get the disposal technique of this bomb drilled into your head right now.
高木 记下拆解那个炸弹的技巧
You've analyzed it, right?
你已经完成分析了吧？
I'll prepare the material right away.
我会立即准备材料
R-Roger that.
收到
...That's what I want to say.
我是很想这么说
I'm actually not good with science and engineering, not to mention, I'm clumsy.
我其实不擅长科学和工程而且我很笨拙
Even so, you wanted to disguise as Matsuda...
即便如此 你还是想乔装成松田…
Hmm, what was Matsuda like in person?
松田是什么样的人啊？
Wild but unexpectedly kind,
狂野但却出人意料的善良
like a shiba-inu and a doberman added together and divided by two?
像柴犬和杜宾犬的结合体吧？
Okay?
什么…？
Hello?
喂？
Get Matsuda on the phone.
让松田接电话
Before we do that, how about you let us hear Chiba's voice?
在那之前 先让我们听听千叶的声音吧？
Get Matsuda on the phone first.
先让松田接电话
If this drags on, you will never hear this detective's voice again.
再这样拖下去 你会永远也听不见那警官的声音了
Hello?
喂？
You will do as I say.
你从现在开始就照我说的去做
Head towards the entrance of Miyashita Park.
前往宫下公园入口
I will call you again.
我会再打给你
Let's go.
出发
Your identities might be exposed.
你的身份可能会被暴露
Use investigators from the PSB for tailing.
让公安部的调查员跟着你
Other than Sergeant Takagi,
除了高木警官
you can confirm the situation through monitors, away from the scene.
其他人可以透过监视器确认现场的情况
(Miyashita Park) Please!
拜托了！
(Currently Under Preparation) How is it?
如何？
Is there anyone suspicious?
有没有任何可疑人物？
No.
没有
Nothing at the moment.
到目前为止什么也没有
Don't let your guard down.
别松懈
We don't know what they're like, or how many there are.
我们不知道对方的长相和人数
Roger that.
收到
Trick or treat!
不给糖就捣蛋！
What's that?
这是什么？
A Halloween event?
万圣节的活动吗？
Trick or treat!
不给糖就捣蛋！
Wow!
哇！
Candies!
糖果！
Give me some!
给我一点！
Ah, that's a new product!
那是新产品！
Can we get these for free?!
我们能免费拿吗？
A Halloween event?!
万圣节活动？
We didn't hear about it!
我们可没听说过！
Hurry and stop them!
快阻止他们！
Lots of candies!
有好多糖果啊！
Great!
太好了！
Yummy!
好好吃哦！
What are you doing!?
你们在干什么！
Hurry and go after them!
快追上他们！
But...
但是…
There are too many people...
人太多了…
Hurry! Don't lose them!
快！别跟丢了！
Hold on!
等一下！
So, you were told to help out as part-time workers?
所以你们是被告知来兼职的吗？
Yes, we were asked to help out for a bit, and we got some money...
是的 我们被叫来帮忙并且能获得酬劳…
Assistant Police Inspector Sato,
佐藤警部补
look at this.
看看这个
This was what Police Sergeant Takagi had on him.
这是高木巡查部长的耳机
I will bring the police dogs over and track his scent.
我会叫警犬来追踪他的气味
Is that alright?
你没意见吧？
Yes.
没有
An underground water storage tank...
一个地下蓄水池…
Remove your mask.
摘下你的头套
My...
真是…
What a strange Halloween.
好奇怪的万圣节
Shiba Inu and Doberman, Shiba Inu and Doberman!
柴犬和杜宾犬 柴犬和杜宾犬！
Detective Matsuda, right?
松田警官 是吧？
Let me confirm Chiba's safety...
让我确认一下千叶的安全…
Come over here.
过来这里
He was put to sleep with some type of anesthesia or drugs...
他只是被麻醉剂或药物弄晕了
I get it, I get it.
我知道了 我知道了
Well, let’s hear it,
说说吧
the reason you brought me here like this…
你用这种方式把我带来这里的原因…
It's my fault for being rough.
我不该对你这么粗暴
I apologize.
我向你道歉
You say that after kidnapping a cop?
这是绑架了警察后该说的话吗？
Detective Matsuda, I won't ask for your understanding.
松田警官 我不会要求你的谅解
However, this is the only option we are left with.
但这是我们唯一的选择
Hey, what are you doing?
你想干什么？
Erenka!
埃莱尼卡！
My name is Erenka Lavrentieva.
我叫埃莱尼卡·拉夫伦切华
(Erenka Lavrentieva) I came here to Japan, following Plamya.
我是跟踪普拉米亚来到日本的
Erenka, what are you trying to do?!
埃莱尼卡 你想干什么？
Revealing your face and name...
竟然暴露了你的长相和名字...
I'm doing this to catch that person with these hands.
这是为了亲手抓住那个人
I see.
原来如此
If you're going to such an extent,
既然你都做到这种程度了
I'll listen to what you have to say.
我就听听你想说的话
It's difficult.
太棘手了
The scent of the candies is distracting the dogs...
糖果的气味分散了警犬们的注意力…
We need to go after them as quickly as possible...
我们需要尽快追上他们…
Hello?
喂？
We know where they are!
我们知道他们在哪里！
It's the underground water storage tank!
是地下蓄水池！
What?!
什么？
We don't know what the source is,
我们不知道影像的来源
but a footage started appearing on the surveillance monitor!
但是画面已经出现在监视器上了
Plamya is a fearsome terrorist who uses special liquid explosives.
普拉米亚是个使用特殊液体炸药的恐怖分子
Countless lives were ended by his hands.
曾有无数人死在他手上
My family, too, was killed by him.
我的家人也被他给杀害了
Everyone here has lost their family or loved ones to those detestable bombs.
所有在这里的人都因为那些可恶的炸弹而失去了家人或所爱的人
We are all comrades who will fight together,
我们都是发誓要一起战斗
swearing vengeance against Plamya.
报复普拉米亚的战友
Alright.
好吧
Us, too.
我们也摘掉吧
We're going after Plamya on our own.
我们靠自己的能力追踪普拉米亚
I see.\
原来如此
So they're a group of civilians.
他们是个民间组织
- That's why they have limited information - Prepare paper and pen.
所以他们掌握的信息有限- 准备纸和笔
and didn't know about Detective Matsuda dying in the line of duty.
不知道松田警官因公殉职了
I understand your situation now.
我了解了你们的情况
So, what do you need me for?
那你们需要我做些什么呢？
Please give us information about Plamya's bomb.
请给我们提供关于普拉米亚炸弹的信息
Three years ago, you defused the bomb that was planted in a building.
三年前 你拆解了安装在建筑物里的炸弹
A few months ago,
几个月前
my brother found the hideout
我哥哥找到了他的藏身处
and went there alone.
并独自一个人去了那里
He successfully stole a tablet.
我哥哥成功偷出了一台平板电脑
And in it...
里面…
There was something that looked like a bomb blueprint,
他看到了类似炸弹蓝图的东西
along with something related to Tokyo.
和一些关于东京的内容
But the screen turned off within seconds.
但屏幕在几秒后就黑掉了
There was nothing he could do to switch it on again.
然后他说他再也打不开它了
Then he said, "It'll be faster to ask someone in Tokyo about matters in Tokyo",
他那时说去东京打探东京的情况会更快
and headed to the MPD.
然后就去了警视厅
And that's why the tablet was slightly burned...
难怪那台平板电脑有被烧毁的痕迹…
But the bomb that killed him was planted in the tablet.
但那个炸死他的炸弹是安装在平板电脑里的
So Plamya had foreseen that the tablet would be taken away, and set up a trap.
也就是说 他预料到了平板电脑会被拿走所以设下了陷阱
I understand the situation now.
我了解现在的情况了
But your brother was also at the scene three years ago.
但你哥哥三年前就出现在案发现场了
What was that about?
那又是为什么？
That was a plan we devised.
那是我们制定的作战计划
We hired Plamya to bomb that building,
我们聘请普拉米亚炸掉那座建筑
and we planned to capture him there.
然后我们打算在那里抓捕他
But the plan failed, and he escaped.
但是计划失败了 他也逃走了
So we were made to bear the consequences of your failure.
我们因此被迫承担你们失败的后果
My brother said the same thing.
我哥哥也是那样说的
He said he wanted to meet Detective Matsuda again.
他说他想再见见松田警官
'We weren't able to defuse Plamya's bomb, but he was.'
他拆解了我们拆解不了的普拉米亚的炸弹
That's why we researched about you,
所以我们调查了你
getting an old picture of you along with very little information.
并在我们掌握的有限信息里得到了一张你的照片
And we also called you here.
然后把你叫来这里
Well, I'm honored.
我还真是荣幸
My family, the people more important than my own life, was murdered.
比我自己的生命还重要的家人被杀害了
I will do anything.
我什么都做得出来
This conversation ends here.
谈话结束了
Draw it out for us, now.
现在就把图画出来给我们
I don't want to.
我拒绝
I can't play along with your personal vengeance.
我不会配合你个人复仇的意图
Damn you!
该死！
This is why I was against this!
所以我才反对这样做！
We don't need help from such a jerk!
我们不需要这种混蛋的帮助！
Detective Matsuda, you don't have a choice.
松田警官你别无选择
Do you not care if anything happens to Detective Chiba?
你难道不担心千叶警官吗？
This matter is too tough for you to handle.
这件事对你来说太难了
We'll arrest him and have him punished...
我们会逮捕他并让他接受审判
So just leave it to the police!
所以交给警察就好了！
Eh?
诶？
Matsuda!?
松田？
No way! Have I died?!
不是吧！我死了吗？
Dead?
死了？
B-Because Matsuda has already died...
因为松田已经因公殉职了…
Chiba, you idiot!
千叶 你这笨蛋！
Damn you!
该死！
Police!
警察！
Everyone, do not move!
所有人都不要动！
Darn! I thought we've warded off the people tailing us...
该死！我以为我们甩开了跟踪我们的人…
How about you stop right there?
你为何不到此为止呢？
Plamya will be the one who benefits the most if we fight among ourselves.
我们之间的冲突只会让普拉米亚得益
Conan?!
柯南？
Did you get the video, too?!
那刚才的影像也是你发给我们的吗？
Kid, do you wish to die!?
孩子 你想死吗！
Hold on! Don't shoot the child!
等等！别向那孩子开枪！
The situation is unfavorable. Let's retreat.
情况对我们不利 先撤退吧
Don't come closer!
别过来！
This isn't a place for a child.
这不是一个孩子该来的地方
We will stop it!
住手吧 我们必须摧毁普拉米亚！
Damn!
糟了！
Hurry up and prepare the lights!
快准备好手电筒！
Don't let them run!
别让他们跑了！
Up, they went up!
上面 他们上去了！
Go after them!
快追！
Darn…
该死…
I don't want you to end up like my son.
我不想你像我儿子一样死去
Find the switch!
找开关！
Hurry!
上面！他们上去了！我们追！- 快！
Is the hostage alright?
人质还好吗？
Over here!
这里！
Takagi!
高木！
Are you alright?!
你没事吧？
Yes… Somehow.
是的… 我没事
Until halfway through, I thought my acting was worthy of the Macademy Awards.
我以为我的演技能让我赢个金像奖
I messed up at the very end...
最后还是被我搞砸了…
Anyway, I'm glad you're okay.
不管怎样 你没事就好了
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
Thank you very much.
谢谢你们
I don’t want you to end up like my son.
我不想你像我儿子一样死去
Son...
儿子…
I was so worried about you!
你让我担心死了！
Hey! N-Naeko, I am alright...
苗子 我没事…
I-I... I am sorry...
我… 对不起…
So, what about the group that escaped?
逃走的那群人呢？
We went after them as quickly as we could, but…
我们尽全力追捕了 可是…
Let's cancel the wedding ceremony.
我们取消婚礼吧
Everyone's safety comes first.
大家的安全优先
But there’s no doubt that Plamya is going after you.
你果然是普拉米亚的目标
We will arrange police protection for you.
从现在开始 你们会受到警方的保护
I'll leave that to you.
拜托你了
Dear! This came in a message!
亲爱的！我收到了这条信息！
(Unknown Number) Carry on with the wedding as planned.
按计划举行婚礼
If you cancel it,
婚礼一旦被取消
there might be more victims...
就可能会有更多的受害者…
What?!
什么？
So we're still proceeding with the wedding, right?
婚礼还是要照常举行对吧？
Yes... This is the only thing we can do.
是的 我们现在也只能这么做
But,
但是
I won't let Plamya get his way.
我不会让普拉米亚得逞的
I will definitely arrest him.
我绝对会把他逮捕归案
Why?
为什么？
Why is Plamya doing all this?
为什么普拉米亚要做这一切…
Even if Mr. Muranaka's wedding ceremony gets canceled,
即使村中先生的婚礼被喊停
he could target them at other locations.
他也可以在其它地方对他们下手
Why is he so persistent about wedding?
为什么执意要在婚礼上下手呢？
What's wrong, Conan?
怎么了 柯南？
You have a scary expression.
你的表情很吓人
I-It's nothing!
啊 没什么！
Ah, I've got a phone call.
啊 有电话来了
I'll be going home!
我要回去了
Be careful on your way back!
一路小心！
Yeah!
嗯
I didn't think you'd contact me.
没想到你会联络我
I want to share this with you as quickly as possible...
我想赶紧让你知道…
I found some information on the organization going after Plamya.
我找到的一些有关追踪普拉米亚那个组织的信息
The organization's name is 'Nado Unichtozhit'.
那个组织的名字是纳多·优尼多兹
They have a network that spans from Russia to Europe,
他们的网络遍布俄罗斯和欧洲
and they track Plamya on their own.
用于自行追踪普拉米亚
Nado Unichtozhit.
纳多·优尼多兹
'Must be extinguished.'
务必摧毁
That means they plan to take Plamya's life...
也就是说他们想要普拉米亚的命…
The leader is a woman who goes by the name 'Erenka'.
头目是一个叫埃莱尼卡的女人
She has a burn scar on her face.
她脸上有一道被火烧伤的疤痕
Frustrated at the halfhearted effort made by the police in various countries,
由于对各国警方的三心二意感到失望
she formed an organization to seek vengeance against Plamya.
她自己成立了一个用于报复普拉米亚的组织
Even though they're just a group of civilians,
尽管是个民间组织
Yes.
我们不知道那是什么意思
so I tried drawing it.
小兰姐姐 你看到那张纸条了？
This symbol... I've seen it somewhere...
这个符号…好像在哪里见过…
Conan?
柯南？
Muranaka received a threat.
村中收到了一封恐吓信
He said it's an important note that he needs to give to someone...
他说那是他要交给某人的重要纸条…
I met her at a hospital.
我是在医院里遇到她的
When I was hospitalized for an injured shoulder.
我因为肩膀受伤而入院
It's a fateful encounter!
那还真是命中注定！
Well, something like that.
是那样没错
The child picked up something that the victim had dropped,
那孩子捡到了受害者掉的东西
and just as she handed it over...
她才刚递过去…
A friend has something she has to give me...
有个朋友有东西要给我…
This is the message that he wanted to show Detective Matsuda?
这是他要给松田警官的纸条吗？
Conan and the Junior Detectives showing up was beyond Plamya’s expectations.
普拉米亚没想到到柯南和少年侦探团会出现在那里
The real target was Muranaka and…
他真正的目标是村中…
We are all comrades who will fight together,
我们都是发誓要一起战斗
swearing vengeance against Plamya.
报复普拉米亚的战友
Carry on with the wedding as planned.
按计划举行婚礼
If you cancel it,
婚礼一旦被取消
there might be more victims...
就可能会有更多受害者...
Here it is, this is where the answer lies...
就在这里 答案就在这…
Conan!
柯南！
What's wrong?
你怎么了？
Look at this.
你看这个
This is the traffic restriction area planned for Halloween.
这是万圣节的交通管制区域
Isn't there a road that goes
不是有一条从丫型道玄坂通往宫益坂下的路吗？
Yes.
是的
Then it intersects Jingu-dori before intersecting
它先穿过神宫通街道
Meiji-dori Avenue that curves around Shibuya Station.
再穿过环绕涩谷站的明治通大街
And if you rotate this map 90 degrees...
如果你把地图旋转九十度…
It'll look like the symbol for yen.
看起来就会很像日圆的符号
The piece of the note I saw happened to have this line burned off,
我看到的那张纸条刚好被烧掉了一条线
so I thought it's a symbol for yen.
所以我以为这是日圆的符号
But Mr. Muranaka and Ms. Christine's wedding would be held in Hikarie, in Shibuya.
但村中先生和克里斯汀小姐的婚礼会在涩谷Hikarie举行
He doesn't have to go through the hassle of drawing it...
他根本不需要把它画出来…
No, it's not just Hikarie.
不 不只是Hikarie
Perhaps, even this area surrounding it too...
可能连周围的这片区域也是…
Conan, you're speaking just like Shinichi!
柯南 你说话的语气跟新一一模一样！
And that was what Big Brother Shinichi said!
这是新一哥哥刚才说的！
You consulted Shinichi about the case again?
你又因为案子去找新一了吗？
Y-Yes.
是的
He said he's solved another mystery as well!
他说他还解开了另一个谜团！
The building explosion that I was involved in
我也在场的那起爆炸案
actually wasn't an attack targeted at Mr. Muranaka.
其实不是针对村中先生的袭击
What do you mean?
什么意思？
We were the target all along.
我们才是他的目标
We were the ones who might have seen this note,
我们都有可能看过这张纸条
so the culprit wanted to eliminate us.
所以犯人想杀掉我们
Hold on.
等等
How would the culprit know the children would be going to that building?
犯人怎么知道你们这些孩子会去那里呢？
It was a time bomb, right?
那是个定时炸弹对吧？
I heard that it was planted ahead of time.
我听说那是提前安装好的
Wasn't there a person who made us head into the building?
不是有人让我们去了那里吗？
Could it be...
难道是…
The person who said there was going to be a meeting with the emcee...
那个说要和司仪开会的人…
The culprit changed their facial features and was hiding in Japan.
犯人改变了他的容貌特征并躲到了日本
That's what a Public Security officer told me.
这是一个公安部的警官告诉我的
That's a problem.
这还真麻烦啊
We have a meeting with the emcee after this...
我们之后还要和婚礼司仪开会…
So the culprit is Tsutomu Muranaka?
所以犯人是村中努？
It's possible to pass off as someone else if they quit their job to live in retirement.
他们是有可能在退休后冒充成其他人
But he was a former police officer!
但他曾经可是一名警察！
The child picked up something the victim had dropped...
那孩子捡到了受害者掉的东西…
Because I told them that...
是我告诉他们的…
You didn't tell them the name of the child back then,
你当时没告诉他们那孩子的名字
so he couldn't determine exactly which child picked it up.
所以他没法确认捡到纸条的孩子是谁
Hence, the plan was to kill everyone in the explosion.
于是他计划炸掉所有人
That's what Big Bro Shinichi told me.
这是新一哥哥告诉我的
How horrible...
好可怕…
And these words...
还有这些字…
These letters are not English. They're Russian.
这些不是英文字母 是俄文
This word above
上面的这行应该是
is probably "пуля", which means bullet.
普亚 也就是子弹
And what is this under it?
这下面是什么？
The number 40...
数字四十...
Big Sis Ran!
小兰姐姐！
I'll go inform the others about this!
我去通知其他人！
Wait!
等一下！
Does that mean Muranaka sent the death threat himself?!
这意思是不是村中给自己发了死亡威胁？
What did Shinichi say?
新一说了什么啊？
Conan!
柯南！
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
To be completely honest,
说实在的
I'm terrified.
我控制不住地感到害怕
We will definitely protect you!
我们绝对会保护你的！
Two people have been killed in Japan, right?
在日本已经有两个人被杀了 对吧？
The bomb planted in that building...
安装在那栋楼里的炸弹…
It's alright.
没事的
We won't let Plamya lay a finger on you.
我们绝不会让普拉米亚动你一根手指头
That was dangerous!
危险！
Lots of people have gathered here at Shibuya!
涩谷这里聚集了很多人
It's Halloween and we're here at Professor's place?
明明是万圣节 我们却只能待在教授这里吗？
How boring...
好无聊啊…
Ayumi wants to go to Shibuya, too.
步美也想去涩谷呢
It can't be helped.
没办法
We can't possibly go there ourselves.
我们不可能自己去
The adults are too busy to be dealing with this.
大人们都太忙了
Let's behave ourselves.
我们就乖乖地待着吧
Ta-da! It's the Funny Hallow-Hallow-Halloween Quiz!
锵锵！有趣的万圣节问答来咯！
It's here…
又来了…
A metropolitan full of high-rise buildings.
在一个高楼林立的都市里
There are police officers right in the middle of it,
有很多警察
working hard to protect the night view.
辛勤守护着城市的人口
Which of the following is doing the job?
请问是哪里的警察在执行任务呢？
Shinjuku Police.
新宿警察
Shibuya Police.
涩谷警察
Shinagawa Police.
品川警察
Ikebukuro Police.
池袋警察
We're not in the mood to solve quizzes.
我们可没心情猜谜语
I'll get hungry if I use my brain.
动脑子我会饿的
I really wanted to go Shibuya...
我真的好想去涩谷...
Ayumi, that's correct!
步美 你答对了！
The answer is Shibuya Police.
答案是涩谷警察
(Shi Bu "Ya Ke i") In the middle,
因为“谷”字里包含了“人口”两个字！
We don't really care.
我们才不管呢
But I spent time thinking about it!
但我还是思考了一下！
Yes, what is it?
有什么事？
What did you say?!
你说什么？
No, but that's still…
不 但还是…
What's wrong, Professor?
怎么了？博士
Who was that from?
是谁发的信息？
Hmm... Was it from Conan?
不会是柯南吧？
N-No, it wasn't!
不 不是！
But... How should I put it...
但是… 我该怎么说呢…
(Please bring the new belt to Shibuya.) Aren't you hiding something from us?
你没有隐瞒我们什么吗？
It's time, let's go.
是时候了 走吧
Wha--?!
什么？
How did you find this place?
你是怎么找到这里的？
When I hit the man behind you with the mask,
我在打中你身后那个带着头罩的男人的时候
I did a little something.
做了点手脚
So you...!
那个时候…！
Erenka, I have something to tell you.
埃莱尼卡 我有话要告诉你
Cut it out! A kid like you...
别闹了！像你这种小孩子…
It's going to be dangerous here tonight.
今晚 这片区域会很危险
Please leave now.
请马上离开这里
I know who Plamya is!
我知道普拉米亚是谁！
You can speak Russian?!
你会说俄语？
You may exchange your rings.
请双方交换戒指
Hey, what's wrong?
怎么了？
Inspector, this is bad!
糟了 警官！
The group of people under warrant is holding a child as hostage…
被通缉的那伙人挟持了一个孩子当人质…
Damn!
该死！
Plamya! Prepare yourself!
普拉米亚！做好觉悟吧！
Don't move!
别动！
Or I'm going to blow this kid's head off.
不然我就打爆这孩子的头
Conan!
柯南！
Drop your guns!
把枪放下！
What are you planning to do?
你想干什么？
I know Plamya's real identity!
我知道普拉米亚的真实身份！
What did you say?!
你说什么？
You two, move aside!
前面的那两个人 快闪开！
The detective at the back,
站在后面的警官
close the doors and lock it up.
把门给锁上
Raise your hands,
把手举起来
Plamya!
普拉米亚！
Wha...?!
什么？
What are you talking about!?
你在说什么？
Plamya is targeting him!
他可是普拉米亚的目标！
Don't move!
别动！
You're the culprit?
你就是犯人？
N-No!
不是！
Why would I be threatening myself?
我怎么会自己恐吓自己呢…
Don't move!
别动！
Both the groom and bride.
新郎和新娘两人
Hurry up and raise your hands.
快把手举起来
What's wrong, bride?
怎么了 新娘？
You, raise your hands, too.
你也把手举起来
Hold on!
等等！
Due to an injury from a traffic accident three years ago,
她在三年前的一起交通事故中受了伤
she can't raise her right shoulder!
右手举不起来！
A traffic accident?
交通事故？
Three years ago, you were shot by a detective in Japan,
三年前 你在日本被一名警察给射伤了
so you can't raise your right shoulder, right?
所以才举不起自己的右手吧？
Am I right,
对吧？
Christine Richard?
克里斯汀·理查德
No,
不
Plamya!
普拉米亚！
You're saying I'm the culprit?
你是在说犯人是我吗？
Cut it out!
够了！
Why is she the culprit?
她怎么会是犯人呢？
This is...?
这是什么？
A metal detector.
金属探测器
There's a bullet embedded
普拉米亚的肩膀里有一颗子弹
inside Plamya's shoulder.
只要靠近她的肩膀就会有所反应
Hold on!
等等！
There's a metal bolt in my shoulder due to surgery...
我的肩膀在手术中装了一颗金属螺栓
Speaking of which,
说到这个
when we were in the dressing room,
我们在更衣室的时候
you said Plamya killed two people in Japan, didn't you?
你说普拉米亚在日本杀了两个人对吧？
The murder of the serial bomber who escaped
关于逃走的连环爆炸案犯人的谋杀案
isn't officially announced, so...
那起案件还没有被公开
Why would you say "two people"?
你怎么会说有两个人呢？
Even you?!
连你也要这样吗？
Wasn’t our wedding supposed to have flawless security?
我们的婚礼安保不是应该无懈可击吗？
But those intruders walked in easily,
但是入侵者轻而易举就能进来
and here we are, treated like criminals…
我们还要被当成犯人一样对待…
This wedding is a mess!
这场婚礼都被搞砸了！
I'm sorry, Christine...
对不起 克里斯汀
To think I am exposed at the very end...
没想到最后还是被发现了…
Christine?
克里斯汀？
What are you…
你这是…
Shut up, shut up!
吵死了…
C-Chris...
克里斯…
Shut up! You're all like buzzing flies!
你们都跟嗡嗡的苍蝇一样！
Take cover!
找掩护！
Everyone, hurry and take cover!
大家 快躲起来！
Conan?!
柯南？
Quick!
快！
O-Okay!
我知道了！
I won't let anyone
我不会让
who knows my real identity live!
任何知道我真实身份的人活着！
Stop it…
别这样…
Christine!
克里斯汀！
Muranaka!
村中！
Inspector Megure!
目暮警官！
Are you alright?!
你没事吧？
Quick, take cover!
快来这里躲着！
Yeah.
我没事
What shall we do?
我们该怎么做？
Stall for time.
拖延时间
I've got one more thing to do!
我还有一件事要做！
Good luck!
祝你好运！
Alright.
好
The bride is the culprit!
新娘就是犯人！
She's on the second floor passage…
她在二楼的过道上…
Let's go through the other entrance!
我们从别的入口进去！
Muranaka, hang in there!
村中 振作起来！
I'm sorry, Megure.
对不起 目暮
I'm really such a fool...
我真傻…
Idiot!
笨蛋！
You've always been a fool!
这也不是什么新鲜事！
Why would you worry about that now?!
你怎么突然醒悟了？
You move your body before you think just as your instinct tells you.
跟着你的直觉行动
You are the Demon Muranaka!
你可是魔鬼村中！
Sato?!
佐藤？
Sato!
佐藤！
Watch out!
小心！
Damn!
该死！
Wait!
等等！
Takagi, you're heavy!
高木 你好重！
We're going after her!
我去追她！
Y-Yes!
好！
She must be heading to the rooftop!
她肯定上天台了！
Is she planning to escape using a helicopter?
她应该是想开直升机逃跑吧？
It's the helicopter they booked as part of the wedding.
那是他们为了婚礼预订的直升机
- We have to hurry! - The police is everywhere.
我们得快点！- 到处都是警察
What are we going to do?
我们下一步该怎么做？
Don't touch the cops.
别对那些警察下手
I made a promise to the boy.
我答应那男孩了
He said he would bring Plamya to us.
他说他一定会把普拉米亚带到我们面前
Let's believe in him.
我们暂且相信他
It's late...
晚了…
I think you should give up already,
我想你该放弃了吧
Christine.
克里斯汀
Well, I should just call you "Plamya", huh?
或者我应该叫你普拉米亚
Who are you?
你是谁？
I'm Conan Edogawa,
我是江户川柯南
a detective.
一名侦探
No way, it's shut.
不行 门被锁了
Detective?
侦探？
Your plan has failed.
你的计划失败了
The plan to kill them all at once.
要把他们都杀光的计划
Erenka and her comrades in Nado Unichtozhit
埃莱尼卡和她组织里的同志们
have been pursuing you around the world.
一直在满世界追踪你
Even someone like Plamya would be driven to the corner.
就算是普拉米亚也会被逼到无路可退
That's why you devised a plan to start afresh.
所以你想到了一个能重新开始的计划
You planned to gather all of them in one place,
你打算把所有人都聚集在一起
and blow them all up with your signature bombs...
然后用你的专属炸弹把他们全炸死...
As expected of someone who calls himself a detective.
不愧是自诩为侦探的人
Young boy, you're right.
你说得对 少年
First, I spread rumors about my retirement.
首先 我散布了关于我要隐退的谣言
Then, I got close to Muranaka...
然后我接近村中…
And then you made up the story about Muranaka being targeted by someone.
然后你编造了村中被某人盯上的故事
If Plamya is involved,
只要涉及到普拉米亚
those people will come chasing.
那些人就会追过来
They would hurry and try to capture me, thinking this would be their final chance.
他们会想办法尽快抓到我觉得这是自己最后的机会
And you have one more goal in mind.
你还有另一个目的
To kill all witnesses.
杀掉所有目击证人
You have killed everyone aware of your identity as Plamya.
你杀死了所有知道你是普拉米亚的人
However…
但是…
Yes, I've tasted humiliation in Japan before…
对 我曾在日本被羞辱过…
Because of those four policemen!
全拜那四名警察所赐！
Your targets are from that time…
从那时起你就盯上了他们…
Bingo.
答对了
After digging deep into the MPD,
对警视厅进行了深入调查之后
I found out Matsuda has already died.
我发现松田已经殉职了
Date died from a traffic accident.
伊达死于交通事故
The only ones remaining are the two men known as Zero and Hiro.
只剩下两个叫零和景光的男人
I only know their names as Furuya and Morofushi,
我只知道他们叫降谷和诸伏
but no matter how hard I searched,
但不管我怎么查
there was no more information on them...
都查不到更多关于他们的信息...
And that's when you used of the serial bomber who killed Matsuda to lure them out.
所以你利用了杀害松田的连环爆炸案犯人试图把他们给引出来
That's right, if I let him escape, they would come out from hiding...
对 如果我让他逃出来他们就会出现…
Just as anticipated, Furuya showed himself,
降谷果然像我预想的那样出现了
and I managed to plant a bomb on him!
我也成功地在他身上安了一颗炸弹！
I thought that would definitely lure the other one out.
我以为这样就一定能引出另一个人
But after doing so much,
但做了这么多
he still hasn't shown himself, and that could only mean...
他还是没有出现 这只能说明…
He's dead, isn't he?
他已经死了 对吧？
The tablet that Erenka's brother, Oleg, was holding on to...
埃莱尼卡的哥哥奥列格拿着的那个平板电脑…
That was a trap, right?
是个陷阱吧？
Exactly.
你说得对
If he'd brought the stolen tablet back to his comrades,
如果他把偷走的平板电脑带给自己的同志
I could blow up the Nado Unichtozhit.
我就能炸了整个纳多·优尼多兹
Instead, he acted independently without joining up with his comrades.
但是他不仅没去找他们 选择单独行动
And planned to tell Matsuda everything.
还打算在找到松田后告诉他一切
Though Matsuda is already dead...
即使松田已经死了…
By watching his movement from the GPS in the tablet,
你通过平板电脑的GPS观察他的动向
you triggered the bomb before he could reach the MPD.
在他还没抵达警视厅之前 就引爆了炸弹
With the keyword of 'Tokyo' in the tablet,
因为平板里有“东京”这个关键词
those people in Nado Unichtozhit took the bait I planted.
纳多·优尼多兹那帮人上钩了
But for that man to find out about the bullet in my shoulder...
但没想到那个男人竟然知道我肩膀上有子弹…
was a miscalculation on my part.
是我失策了
We found out because of the note left by Oleg.
我们是通过奥列格留下的纸条知道的
"Bullet" and "shoulder".
子弹和肩膀
Three years ago, Plamya was also shot in the shoulder.
三年前 普拉米亚的肩膀也中弹了
They told me removing the bullet would damage my nerve,
他们说取出子弹会伤到神经
and that would affect the movement in my right arm...
而且会影响右手的动作…
That's a lethal injury to your ability to build intricate bombs!
这对你制造复杂炸弹的能力可是个致命打击！
So you gave up removing the bullet.
所以你放弃了手术
In return, you can't lift your right arm anymore, and that's the truth.
作为代价 你的右臂再也擡不起来了
Where did you plant the bomb?
你把炸弹装在了哪里？
What can you do about it at this point?
都这个时候了 你还能做什么呢？
Your identity has been exposed to the police, Nado Unichtozhit, and many other people.
警察 纳多·优尼多兹还有很多人都知道了你的身份
Isn't it pointless to carry out the explosion now?
你现在引爆炸弹还有什么意义吗？
I believe I said this earlier.
我想我说过
Anyone who knows my identity shall not be allowed to live.
任何知道了我身份的人都得死
All these clueless fools gathering here.
那些聚集在这里的笨蛋
I bet they thought those are just Halloween decoration to liven up the mood.
他们应该以为那些东西仅仅是活跃气氛的万圣节装饰
Could it be...?!
不会吧？
Those lanterns?!
那些灯笼？
I've planted dummies and liquid explosives around Dogenzaka and Miyamasuzaka.
我在道玄坂和宫益坂安装了带有液体炸药的南瓜灯
The liquid will flow to the lowest point,
液体会流向最低点
or in other words, it would all gather at the scramble crossing.
也就是说 两种液体会在交叉路口那里燃爆
I see.
原来如此
You're planning to use the elevation difference in Shibuya...
你打算利用涩谷的地形…
The massive amount of liquid explosives
大量的液体炸药
would create an unprecedentedly huge explosion.
会引发前所未有的巨大爆炸
And everyone who knows of my identity
所有知道我身份的人
will disappear from this world!
都会从这个世界上消失！
And that's what I wanted to hear.
这正是我想听的
Damn, you are...
该死 你是…
Rei Furuya?!
降谷零？
We could've captured you any time...
我随时都可以抓捕你
But we had to let you get this far
但我们必须放任你到现在
to find out the location of the bomb.
才能知道炸弹的安置地点
Well, though it's partly foreseeable from that drawn symbol.
虽然从那个符号中也能猜到一二
You damn brat...
臭小子…
Plamya!
普拉米亚！
You have no way to escape!
你逃不掉了！
I guess this is the end for me.
可能这就是我的结局了
Put your hand up...
把手举起来…
And put it behind your head.
双手抱头
Yea.
是
Al... right!
我...知道了！
At this stage, I can only take out as many of you as I can!
到了这个时候 我也只能杀一个算一个了！
Wha...!
什么！
Go!
上！
It missed!
没打中！
Not yet!
还没结束！
Hit it!!
打中它！
Fireworks ball!
烟花球！
Darn!
该死！
As a precaution, I have a spare ready.
为了以防万一 我还有一个备用的
I'll send you to the other world first.
我先把你给送上西天
With that collar bomb!
就用那个项圈炸弹！
What?!
什么？
I thought this would happen,
我早料到了
so we returned you the gift you gave us.
所以我们把你送的礼物还给你了
It's a dummy?!
那是假的吗？
The liquid explosives were thoroughly analyzed,
我们已经完成了液体炸药的分析
and a neutralizer was made
而我优秀的下属
by my capable subordinate.
也已经制出了中和剂
And that liquid was produced by us, how do you like it?
那些液体都是我们做的 你还喜欢吗？
Furuya!
降谷！
Wait for me below!
下去等我！
Amuro!
安室！
I won't let you escape this time.
我不会再让你逃走的！
I hate persistent men!
我讨厌穷追不舍的男人！
What a reckless move!
他太鲁莽了！
He leaped onto the helicopter to fight the culprit...
竟然跳上直升机跟犯人搏斗…
Conan, do you know him?
柯南 你认识那人吗？
I couldn't see his face behind the culprit.
他被犯人挡着 我看不见他的脸
Let's head down!
快下楼！
Wait!
等等！
Who is that pilot?!
那个飞行员是谁？
Eh? Seriously?
真的假的？
Isn't that bad?
会坠机吧？
Let go, you jerk!
放手 你这混蛋…
Your goal will no longer come true.
我不会让你得逞
Too bad!
可惜了！
Damn!
该死！
Get away from Shibuya, quick!
请大家离开涩谷 快！
There's a possibility of a terror attack!
这可能是恐怖袭击！
Evacuate as soon as possible!
尽快疏散！
Please stay away from the station!
请远离车站！
Hurry!
快点！
What's the commotion about?
这骚动是怎么回事？
It'll be faster to walk there.
走过去会更快
According to the message Conan sent,
根据柯南发来的指令
we have to go wait for him at the center of the intersection.
我们要在十字路口中间等他
That's what he wrote, right?
他是那样写的吧？
Bringing this with us.
要带着这个
Professor, can we go?
我们能去吗 博士？
Well...
这个…
There's no other choice.
我们也别无选择了
Let's run!
用跑的！
Yeah!
是！
Be very careful!
小心点！
Is this enough to stop the explosion?
这能阻止爆炸吗？
All because of you.
都是因为你
All because of a jerk like you,
都是因为你这个混蛋
my plan is completely ruined!
我的计划被彻底摧毁了！
Die!
去死吧！
As a former policeman, I can't let you commit more crimes.
作为一名前警察我不能让你继续犯罪了
You're...
你是…
You should leave this place immediately.
你必须马上离开这里
What?
什么？
You shouldn't be here, right?\
你在这里不好吧？
Aren't you with the Public Security Bureau?
你不是公安部的人吗？
How did you know?!
你是怎么知道的？
I've been a policeman for a long time.
我当了很多年的警察
I just know it, from my instinct...
是我的直觉告诉我的…
But it seems like my instinct didn't work when it came to my fiancée...
但对于我的未婚妻 我的直觉却没起作用…
Don't worry, I won't tell the others about you.
别担心 我不会告诉目暮和其他人的
If we manage to survive this.
如果我们能活下来
Shoot her here and now.
现在就开枪把她杀了
Kirill... I will avenge you, my son...
西里尔...我这就为你报仇 我的儿子…
No!
不！
Don't shoot, Erenka!
别开枪 埃莱尼卡！
Move aside, young boy!
闪开 少年！
I'll shoot you too if you get in my way!
如果你妨碍我 我也会向你开枪！
Even if you shoot Plamya, you can't bring your son back.
你杀了普拉米亚也没办法救活你的儿子
What do you know?!
你什么都不知道！
My son, my husband, and my older brother,
我的儿子 丈夫和哥哥
they were all killed by her!
都被她给杀死了！
I can no longer return to my former life!
我再也回不去以前的生活了！
I've done plenty of bad things too!
我也做了很多坏事！
All in order to kill her!
都是为了能杀死她！
I sacrificed everything to get this chance!!
我为了这一刻牺牲了一切！
I won’t be satisfied if I don't kill her with my own hands!
只有亲手杀了她才能解我心头之恨！
Move aside, young boy!
闪开 少年！
Why did they have to be killed?
他们为什么要死？
My husband was a policeman,
我丈夫是个警察
and all he did was to arrest a murder suspect whose parent is a politician!
他只是逮捕了一个父亲是政客的谋杀案嫌疑人！
They tried to erase us after testifying in court,
他们在出庭后想杀人灭口连我儿子都不放过
Did my husband or son do anything wrong?
我的丈夫和儿子到底做错了什么？
Hey, tell me...
告诉我...
We will definitely bring her to justice.
我们一定会将她绳之以法
So please, trust the Japanese police.
所以请相信日本警察
Erenka, I need your help.
埃莱尼卡 我需要你的帮助
To prevent any more tragedies from happening, I need help from everyone.
为了防止更多悲剧发生我需要你们每个人的帮助
Let's stop Plamya's bomb together.
务必摧毁
Conan!
柯南！
Where are you?
你在哪？
Ah!
啊！
You guys! Why are you all here?!
你们怎么都在这里啊？
Let's talk later.
我们晚点再说
We got this from the professor.
我们从教授那里拿到了这个
Here, this is the new belt.
这是新的腰带
Thank you.
谢谢
Darn it, we don't have much time left.
该死 我们没多少时间了
There's no other choice.
没办法了
You've seen my message to Professor, right?
你们看了我发给博士的信息了吧？
Can you handle it?
你能做到吗？
Yes.
当然
We have to hold the end of this suspender and run...
我们抓住这个背带的一边然后跑...
Then secure it around guardrails or traffic lights, right?
然后把它固定在护栏或者交通灯上 对吧？
A piece of cake!
小事一桩！
We'll use the detective badges to signal Edogawa once we're done.
完成后 我们会用侦探徽章向你发出信号
You can do it, right?
知道了吗？大家？
Yeah!
是！
Get in touch with the others.
去联络其他人
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
This could be our last chance...
这可能是我们最后的机会…
We cannot let more people become like us.
我们不能让更多人陷入悲剧
Okay.
好
Muranaka!
村中！
Megure!
目暮！
You came just in time.
你来得正是时候
Have you got her?
你抓到她了？
Yea, I'll leave the rest to you.
是的 剩下的就交给你们了
I have to go now.
我得走了
Eh? Where are you going?
什么？你要去哪里？
It's flowing fast.
液体流得好快
Hurry up!
快点！
Just a little more!
就差一点点…
I will help.
我来帮你
Do I just tie it here?
把它绑在这里就好了吗？
Let me help you.
让我来帮你
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you!
谢谢！
Ready!
准备好了！
Alright!
很好！
It has already reached here...
已经流到这里了…
Hurry!
快点…
Ayumi!
步美！
Ayumi, hang in there!
步美 撑住！
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
That’s a serious wound!
你伤得很严重！
Why didn't you say anything?!
你怎么都没说？
We can't possibly leave now...
我们不可能现在就离开…
We have to hold this down...
我们得抓住这个…
Fine, I understand!
我明白了！
Edogawa!
江户川！
It'll be bad if the ball expands anymore!
如果球再膨胀下去就不好了！
We have to secure it to something more durable!
我们必须把它固定在更牢固的东西上…
We can't do this just by ourselves!
凭我们几个是做不到的！
Darn!
该死！
We need more people, but...
我们需要更多人 可是…
- Takagi! - Detective Takagi!
高木！- 高木警官！
Everyone was evacuated!
所有人都被疏散了！
There's no other people around!
没有其他人了！
At this rate, Shibuya will be engulfed in flames...
再这样下去 整个涩谷都会被火焰吞噬…
Ran!
兰…
Shinichi?
新一？
Hang in there, Takagi!
撑住 高木！
We will help you, young boy.
我们会帮你的 少年
Sergey! Everyone!
谢尔盖！所有人！
Erenka, you are our leader.
埃莱尼卡 你是我们的首领
We'll follow the path you lead us on.
我们会跟随你的脚步
Everyone agreed.
所有人都答应了
Don't take it all on yourself.
别一个人扛着
Thank you.
谢谢你
Ready... Pull!
预备… 拉！
This should be good enough now.
现在应该可以了
We have secured this side too!
这边也固定了！
It's perfect!
完美！
Mission complete!
任务完成！
Thank you, you all!
谢谢你们！
Who is he really, that boy?
那男孩到底是谁？
Conan!
柯南！
Go!
冲！
Hold on tight!
抓紧！
It's stopped.
停下来了
Here you are.
原来你在这啊
Is everything going to be alright?
应该没事了吧？
We just need another one hour or so,
只需要再过一个小时
and it'll be completely neutralized.
所有液体就能被中和掉了
As expected from the PSB, so efficient.
不愧是公安部 真有效率
You are more impressive.
你更厉害
How did you come up with that solution?
你是怎么想出这个方法的？
I got a hint from someone...
我得到了某个人的提示…
It was quite a long time ago...
那是很久以前的事了…
It's all Shinichi's fault for hitting the ball at such a bad spot...
都怪新一把球踢到这里…
Stop crying, Ran. It'll be alright.
别哭了 兰 会没事的
Darn!
真是的！
Hey, boy!
喂 孩子！
Don't make your woman cry.
别弄哭你的女人啊
It stopped!
成功了！
Hagi, what are you doing?
萩 你在做什么？
Jinpei! Phone!
阵平！打电话！
Call the Bureau of Waterworks!
联络水务局！
What? Why?!
什么？为什么？
I suddenly remembered that.
我突然想起来那件事
And I thought I can stop the explosion using the same method...
我想我也可以用同样的方法阻止爆炸…
That person kind of resembled that Hagiwara guy.
那人长得很像那个叫萩原的人…
Is anything wrong?
怎么了？
No,
没有
it's nothing.
没事
Strange... They were here just now!
奇怪… 他们刚才还在这里的！
Where did they go?
他们都去哪了？
We were all saved because of their help!
有了他们的帮助 我们才得救的！
If they hadn't been here,
如果不是他们
Shibuya will be engulfed in flames right now.
涩谷现在已经被火焰给吞噬了
Takagi!
高木！
Hang in there!
撑住！
Sato...
佐藤…
Hey, lend me a hand!
喂！帮帮我！
Yes!
是！
Sato,
佐藤
I think, I will have to undergo a surgery after this...
我想我应该会被推进手术室…
Y-Yes.
是的
Can I have a lucky charm for that?
我能跟你讨个幸运符吗？
Lucky charm?
幸运符？
Sheesh...
真是的…
If you still have that much strength, you’ll be fine.
你还有力气想这些 你肯定会没事的
Sato...
佐藤…
Takagi!
高木！
How dare you just die like that.
你怎么可以就这样死去
You idiot!
笨蛋！
Restrain them!
抓住他们！
You thugs!
你们这些暴徒！
Go, go!
上！
Yes!
对！
That's right!
这就对了！
Wait, I was just resting in the hospital
等等 我刚刚还在医院里休息
What's going on now?!
发生什么事了？
What are you doing?!
你们在干什么？
Don't let your guard down just because it’s a drill!
别因为这是一场演习就放松警惕！
Yes!
是！
Do...
我…
Do I have to be in this attire?
我非得穿成这样吗？
Hey!
喂！